<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>


<channel>
	<title>TorrentFreak</title>
	<atom:link href="https://torrentfreak.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://torrentfreak.com/</link>
	<description>Breaking File-sharing, Copyright and Privacy News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:41:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Operator of South Korea&#8217;s Largest Pirate Site Sentenced to 3 Years in Prison</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/operator-of-south-koreas-largest-pirate-site-sentenced-to-3-years-prison-250604/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noonootv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nunutv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=268156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Before its inevitable demise, NooNooTV [NunuTV] was believed to be the largest pirate site in South Korea. That in itself made the site's operator a prime target for enforcement. Despite spawning dozens of domains to avoid blocking, and reportedly moving servers from one 'safe' country to another, local authorities continued their investigation in collaboration with INTERPOL. At a court in South Korea last week, 'Person A' was sentenced to three years in prison.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-logo.png"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-logo.png" alt="noonoo-logo" width="270" height="271" class="alignright size-full wp-image-232178" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-logo.png 270w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-logo-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 270px) 100vw, 270px" /></a>As online piracy continued to cause headaches for South Korea, in 2023 key media entities formed the Video Copyright Protection Council. </p>
<p>The VCPC coalition adopted a unified &#8220;stronger together&#8221; strategy for operational efficiencies and greater governmental leverage, swiftly putting its first target on notice with a criminal complaint and a <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/ace-new-anti-piracy-coalition-target-south-korean-video-piracy-230309">$3.7 billion damages claim</a>.  </p>
<h2>NunuTV / NooNooTV</h2>
<p>Popular in the local market, streaming site NunuTV (or Noonootv based on domain name format) had been servicing tens of millions of visitors per month and was reportedly responsible for 1.5 billion views of pirated movies and TV shows. </p>
<p>With billions of dollars worth of damage allegedly suffered by legitimate platforms, NunuTV became a clear candidate for aggressive site-blocking measures. The authorities blocked domain after new domain but nothing seemed capable of significantly reducing the site’s popularity.</p>
<p>Coupled with a warning from the coalition, an announcement that the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism, would create a new piracy investigation unit, in hindsight signaled the beginning of the end for NunuTV.</p>
<p><center><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-tv.png"><img decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-tv.png" alt="noonoo-tv" width="600" height="313" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-232170" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-tv.png 1100w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/noonoo-tv-300x157.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></center></p>
<p>Less than two years after its launch in June 2021, the site <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/korean-piracy-giant-noonoo-tv-shuts-down-citing-banwidth-costs-pressure-230414/">announced</a> that it would shut down on April 14, 2023, citing &#8220;outrageous&#8221; bandwidth costs and &#8220;pressure on the site from all directions.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Site Down, Legal Subscribers Up, Hail Blocking</h2>
<p>The site&#8217;s closure was cause for cautious celebration. In a July 2023 <a href="https://cjenmir.irplus.co.kr/fileupload/analyst_e/202307/20230712_cjenm1.pdf">report</a> published by subscription streaming platform Tving, a growing subscriber base was attributed to customer loyalty and the closure of NunuTV. In the United States, the tactics used against the site highlighted were seen as important.</p>
<p>After nominating the site for &#8216;notorious market&#8217; status in 2022 <small><em><a href="https://www.motionpictures.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/MPA_2022-Notorious-Markets.pdf">(pdf)</a></em></small>, the MPA&#8217;s 2023 submission <small><em>(<a href="https://www.motionpictures.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/MPA_2023-Notorious-Markets-10.6.23.pdf">pdf</a>)</em></small>, attributed the site&#8217;s demise to the success of site blocking and the and the Ministry of Culture&#8217;s announcement regarding its investigation team..</p>
<h2>Season 2: Surprisingly Short</h2>
<p>In the background, the emergence of a new site just weeks after the disappearance of the first, had already prompted an announcement by the government.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-season2.png" alt="nunutv-season2" width="300" height="212" class="alignright size-full wp-image-268193" /></p>
<p>Aggressive site blocking was back on the table, with blocks updated several times each day. It remained to be seen what other “strong measures” could be taken that hadn’t been tried before.</p>
<p>Quite quickly, however, the problem found its own solution.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Hello, this is NunuTV Season 2. After careful consideration, the NunuTV Season 2 site is closed. Although it is a short period of time, we sincerely appreciate your interest.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>With over 1,300 domains containing &#8220;noonootv&#8221; registered and ready for use, copycat sites were always likely to be a problem. Yet, minus the features that made the original so popular, few if any could expect anything like the same success. </p>
<p>As is often the case with site resurrections, only those behind the original site could realistically deliver the same experience. Late last year, the chances of that happening collapsed in an instant.</p>
<h2>Operator of NunuTV Arrested in South Korea</h2>
<p>In November 2024, Korean authorities <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/piracy-kingpin-behind-noonoo-tv-and-tvwiki-arrested-in-korea-241112/">announced the shutdown of TVWIKI</a>, a popular streaming piracy site with millions of users. A special unit under the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism arrested the site&#8217;s alleged operator, who according to reports, was also behind streaming platform OKTOON. </p>
<p>A takedown notice <a href="https://copyright241109.github.io/noonoowarrant/">hosted on GitHub</a> revealed that the individual, identified only as &#8216;Person A&#8217;, was also the operator of NunuTV. </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/minis-warrant.png" alt="minis-warrant" width="600" height="215" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268211" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/minis-warrant.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/minis-warrant-300x108.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/minis-warrant-150x54.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Concerns that the raids and arrest were an of elaborate hoax were soon dismissed by Korean authorities. </p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-arrest.png" alt="nunutv-arrest" width="670" height="486" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268209" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-arrest.png 707w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-arrest-300x218.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-arrest-600x435.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-arrest-150x109.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>According to local news reports, law enforcement authorities seized assets worth 2.6 billion won (US$1.9m) including two luxury cars, and a total of 14 bitcoin.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-porsche.png" alt="nunutv-porsche" width="670" height="375" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268219" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-porsche.png 1354w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-porsche-300x168.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-porsche-600x335.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-porsche-150x84.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>Six months later, &#8216;Person A&#8217; appeared before a court in South Korea to discover how his immediate future would be playing out.</p>
<h2>Sentenced to 3 Years in Prison, $500K Fine</h2>
<p>On May 26, Judge Koh Young-sik at the 9th Criminal Division of the Daejeon District Court, <a href="https://www.yna.co.kr/view/AKR20250526117751063">sentenced</a> &#8216;Person A&#8217; for offenses under the Copyright Act. </p>
<p>&#8220;The nature of the crime is bad because it systematically infringed on property rights over a long period of time for profit-making purposes such as obtaining advertising revenue,&#8221; Judge Koh said. </p>
<p>To avoid the effects of site blocking and other government action, Person A continued to operate using dozens of domains and overseas servers, including in the Dominican Republic and Paraguay. Virtual private networks (VPNs), overseas credit cards, and cryptocurrencies were also used in an effort to avoid being tracked down by investigators.</p>
<p>To obtain content from legal webtoon platforms, Person A reportedly obtained official accounts from an unspecified number of people before posting illegal copies online. A diagram supplied by the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism provides an overview of the operation.</p>
<p><center><em>Image credit: Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism (text TF)</em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-diagram-FIN.png" alt="nunutv-diagram" width="670" height="824" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268173" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-diagram-FIN.png 917w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-diagram-FIN-300x369.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-diagram-FIN-600x738.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/nunutv-diagram-FIN-122x150.png 122w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>&#8220;Copyright crimes not only infringe on the copyright holder&#8217;s ability to generate revenue, but also discourage creative desire, ultimately hindering cultural development,&#8221; Judge Koh continued.</p>
<p>&#8220;In addition, the defendant admitted his wrongdoing, and his criminal record was taken into consideration when determining the sentence.&#8221;</p>
<p>For the illegal distribution of hundreds of thousands of copyrighted videos and webtoons via NunuTV, TVWiki, and OKTOON, the former pirate site operator was ordered to serve three years in prison and pay a fine of 700 million won (US$512K)</p>
<h2>Odds of Evasion: Slim</h2>
<p>Reports claim that NunuTV&#8217;s operator was “meticulous” in his efforts to remain anonymous but when local government and law enforcement agencies team up with international partners, that may not be enough. Person A was the target of a joint investigation by the Copyright Crime Scientific Investigation Unit of the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism, and the International Criminal Police Organization, better known as INTERPOL.</p>
<p>In January 2025, INTERPOL announced the signing of a memorandum of understanding and launch of the second phase of INTERPOL-Stop Online Piracy (I-SOP), an international collaborative anti-piracy project to crack down on illegal online distribution platforms. </p>
<p>The initiative receives funding from the Korean Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism (MCST) (2.8 million euros) with support from the Korean National Police Agency. </p>
<p>In addition to the dismantling of NunuTV, successes during the first phase include the <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/police-confirm-fbi-assisted-takedown-of-piracy-release-group-evo-230405/">arrest of individuals</a> behind P2P release group EVO.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/interpol-korea-1a.png" alt="" width="670" height="260" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268223" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/interpol-korea-1a.png 1952w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/interpol-korea-1a-300x116.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/interpol-korea-1a-600x233.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/interpol-korea-1a-150x58.png 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/interpol-korea-1a-1536x596.png 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MPA Backs Automated Pirate Site-Blocking, Sees Role for VPN and CDN Companies</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/mpa-backs-automated-pirate-site-blocking-sees-role-for-vpn-and-cdn-companies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 19:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Site Blocking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Motion Picture Association sees automated, real-time, and dynamic site blocking mechanisms as a key tool to fight online piracy. In response to an inquiry from the European Commission, reviewing its recommendation to combat live-streaming piracy, the MPA further notes that VPN companies and CDN providers should be actively involved. </p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/blockeddonotenter.jpg" alt="blocked" width="300" height="190" class="alignright size-full wp-image-190345" />In recent years, the European Commission has proposed and adopted various legislative changes to help combat online piracy.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/eu-parliament-adopts-copyright-directive-including-article-13-190326/">Copyright Directive</a> and the <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/eus-digital-services-act-proposes-new-content-removal-rights-and-rules-201215/">Digital Services Act</a> both envisioned tighter copyright takedown rules for online service providers.</p>
<p>Many rightsholder groups felt that the new rules were insufficient to target live streaming piracy, sports content in particular. They wanted more incentives for online service providers to act faster and more diligently, as suspensions are useless after a live broadcast ends. </p>
<p>The EU Commission heard these calls and published a <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_23_2508">targeted recommendation</a> &#8216;on combating online piracy of sports and other live events&#8217;, encouraging member states to introduce measures to facilitate prompt takedowns of live streams. At the same time, service providers and rightsholders were encouraged to collaborate, to tackle the challenge together. </p>
<p>Over two years later, the European Commission recently launched a call for evidence, asking stakeholders to share their views on the recommendation. Based on its assessment, the Commission will evaluate whether further EU-level measures are needed to tackle the issue. </p>
<h2>MPA: Site Blocking is Key</h2>
<p>Last week, the Motion Picture Association (MPA) submitted its comments on the effectiveness of the 2023 recommendation. Representing prominent movie industry players including Netflix, Disney, and Warner Bros. Discovery, it has a significant stake in the matter. </p>
<p>Overall, the MPA is positive about the EU legal framework, noting that it provides valuable tools such as site blocking injunctions. However, implementation of these measures across EU member states is inconsistent and in some countries, cumbersome or completely absent.</p>
<p>Site blocking measures have been available under EU law for more than two decades, but not all EU countries implemented them correctly, MPA says, mentioning Germany, Poland, and Bulgaria as examples. </p>
<p>&#8220;Despite the Commission’s Recommendation, Europe is missing effective and appropriate implementation of these provisions across all Member States. Germany has not correctly implemented Article 8(3) InfoSoc nor Article 11 IPRED, whereas Poland and Bulgaria have not implemented these provisions at all,&#8221; MPA writes.  </p>
<p>In Germany, for example, copyright holders must take steps to identify the operator of piracy sites before they can request blocking measures. In some cases, this requires pursuing legal action against hosting companies. </p>
<p>This is a barrier that makes site blocking unnecessarily complicated or costly, MPA says. That&#8217;s counterproductive in an environment where pirate sites and services are quick to adapt their strategies. </p>
<p>&#8220;Swift action is needed to limit the dissemination and damage of copyright infringement,&#8221; MPA stresses.</p>
<h2>Automated Real-Time Blocking</h2>
<p>Automated solutions already exist in some countries. The MPA is particularly interested in site blocking schemes that allow rightsholders to automatically add new piracy domains in realtime. </p>
<p>This is especially important for live broadcasts, including sports events, as these have a small blocking window. The MPA says that these broadcasts require dynamic siteblocking and fast-track legal procedures in order to be protected.   </p>
<p>&#8220;MPA is therefore supportive of automated effective siteblocking mechanisms that can be updated in realtime with appropriate safeguards to address emerging infringing streams. In Italy, Greece, Portugal and Brazil automated dynamic systems are available to rightsholders allowing effective real-time blocks.&#8221;</p>
<p>Automated blocking measures also help to combat circumvention. Pirate site operators are generally quick to circumvent blocking measures with new domain names. Their users can typically find new pirate sites though search engines and social media. </p>
<p>&#8220;When a pirate service is blocked, pirate infringing operators register and activate a new domain—often with a similar name—allowing users to regain access, therefore circumventing the initial blocking order,&#8221; MPA writes.</p>
<h2>CDNs, VPNs and other Intermediaries</h2>
<p>Collaboration between Internet providers and copyright holders is essential to implement effective blocking mechanisms, MPA says. However, other intermediaries should also be brought into the fold. </p>
<p>MPA suggests a more active role for reverse proxy providers, content delivery networks (CDNs) hosting providers, VPNs and search engines. These were also highlighted in the EU Commission&#8217;s 2023 recommendation. </p>
<p>The group notes that cooperation with CDNs (e.g. Cloudflare) is key to properly enforcing dynamic blocking.</p>
<p>&#8220;Intermediaries such as CDNs also have the technical capability to implement targeted blocking at the infrastructure level, which can be a highly effective complement to traditional siteblocking, especially where operators rely on CDN services to deliver pirated content at scale.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Their engagement tends to be necessary to make targeted and technically feasible siteblocking possible. Failing to involve these actors undermines the effectiveness of dynamic injunctions, as pirates increasingly rely on them to obscure their infrastructure and evade enforcement.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Identifying Pirates</h2>
<p>In addition to helping on the blocking side, MPA also sees a role for these intermediaries when it comes to identifying pirate site operators. To achieve this, rightsholders should be able to use &#8220;Right of Information&#8221; requests to swiftly identify potential targets. </p>
<p>These information requests should be made available under EU law and, just as importantly, the EU should expand Know Your Business Customer (KYBC) requirements to online intermediaries. At the moment, KYBC rules only apply to online marketplaces. </p>
<p>&#8220;To effectively allow the identification of the source and repeated misuse of their services, intermediaries need to ensure that they obtain accurate and complete customer information,&#8221; MPA writes, adding that KYBC requirements are an &#8220;ideal tool&#8221; with &#8220;minimal burdens&#8221; for the intermediaries involved.</p>
<p>All in all, the MPA believes that Europe is largely on the right track with its anti-piracy efforts and policies, but with the suggested improvements, ideally formalized in legislation, the process can be further improved. </p>
<h2>Rightsholders United</h2>
<p>The MPA is not the only stakeholder making these types of demands. A wide variety of other rightsholder organizations, representing various sectors of the creative industries, echoed the call for more robust anti-piracy measures with legislative backing across the European Union. </p>
<p>For example, MFE-MEDIAFOREUROPE, which controls major broadcasters like Mediaset, stressed that hosting providers, CDN providers, and payment services need to take more decisive action. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, DAZN described the DSA as a missed opportunity to specifically target entities like VPN providers, dedicated server hosts, and CDN services that play a role in facilitating online piracy. Both DAZN and MFE joined the MPA in calling for KYBC obligations to be extended to more intermediaries.</p>
<p>Ultimately, these submissions paint a picture of rightsholders acknowledging the EU&#8217;s efforts, while highlighting a clear need for further, stronger action at the EU level. The European Commission will typically take its time to evaluate this feedback, while also keeping an eye on those that are more critical of recent anti-piracy efforts. </p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>A copy of the Motion Picture Association submission in response the EU Commission&#8217;s assessment of the May 2023 Commission Recommendation to combating online piracy of sports and other live events is available <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/mpacomment.pdf">here (pdf)</a>.</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anti-Piracy Group BREIN Ramps Up IPTV Actions Under New Leadership</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/anti-piracy-group-brein-ramps-up-iptv-actions-under-new-leadership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 06:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brein]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=268112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dutch anti-piracy group BREIN has just posted its latest annual report, highlighting several key achievements. IPTV continues to be the largest threat to the audiovisual industry. In addition to shutting down dozens of operators, BREIN made criminal referrals that it expects to pay off this year. Google also lent a helping hand by banning adverts for 'IPTV' keyword searches. </p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/brein24-600x356.jpg" alt="brein 2024" width="300" height="178" class="alignright size-large wp-image-268123" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/brein24-600x356.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/brein24-300x178.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/brein24-150x89.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/brein24-220x130.jpg 220w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/brein24.jpg 949w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />BREIN has just published its latest annual report, providing insights into the priorities of the organization and the progress being made. </p>
<p>This was BREIN’s first year under new leadership. After Tim Kuik retired in 2024, Bastiaan van Ramshorst became the new director flanked by Birre Büller, the new head of legal affairs.</p>
<h2>BREIN&#8217;s 2024 Annual Report</h2>
<p>Last week, the group published its 2024 annual report which shows that anti-piracy activities continue undeterred. BREIN completed 339 cases last year, of which 179 were marked as extensive investigations. As a result, 40 settlements were reached, including 7 &#8220;knock &#038; talks&#8221;.</p>
<p>In addition to these dedicated investigations, BREIN also continued its regular operations. This includes updating the pirate site blocklist used by local ISPs, to which 525 unique domains were added last year. At the end of 2024, 574 domains were blocked, up from 208 at the start of the year.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/blockedbrei.jpg" alt="BREIN blocked" width="600" height="343" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-268121" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/blockedbrei.jpg 1461w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/blockedbrei-300x171.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/blockedbrei-600x343.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/blockedbrei-150x86.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<p>The new target domain names were also reported to Google, which voluntarily removed these 525 domains from its search results. That comes in addition to the 166,945 individual Google search results BREIN asked the company to remove. </p>
<h2>IPTV Action Intensifies</h2>
<p>The voluntary cooperation of Google is noteworthy and doesn&#8217;t stop at delisting blocked domains. The company also helped to prevent the promotion of pirate IPTV services through its advertising business. This led to the drastic decision where Google updated its policy to no longer allow ads for the search term &#8220;IPTV&#8221;.</p>
<p>As a result of this policy change, BREIN reported fewer IPTV advertisements last year. According to BREIN, action by Google was in part taken in response to complaints from the Dutch anti-piracy group. </p>
<p>These restrictions are part of a broader theme in which IPTV is increasingly recognized as a major piracy threat. According to BREIN, IPTV is now considered the biggest threat to the audiovisual content industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Dutch fiscal police (FIOD) officially designated IPTV as a phenomenon in 2024. This means higher priority and more budget for combating illegal IPTV. As a result, there is more room for investigation and ultimately more criminal cases,&#8221; BREIN writes </p>
<p>&#8220;Illegal IPTV also has the full attention of Europol, Eurojust and the EUIPO. Among other things, this regularly leads to criminal actions in the Netherlands at the request of foreign investigative agencies. Where possible, BREIN and foreign sister organizations of BREIN contribute to this.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Criminal Action and Boots on the Ground</h2>
<p>The added attention to the IPTV problem has resulted in several new criminal referrals by BREIN last year. The group expects that this will lead to new arrests and potential prosecutions in 2025, but as these investigations are ongoing, further details are currently unavailable.</p>
<p>&#8220;These cases are expected to result in arrests in 2025. Because of ongoing criminal investigations, BREIN can only make announcements about them after arrests have been made,&#8221; BREIN writes.</p>
<p>These IPTV actions are not limited to online operations; they also extend to offline marketplaces. Since the <a href="https://debazaar.nl/en/">Beverwijk Bazaar</a> is seen as a hotspot for this activity in the Netherlands, BREIN has signed an agreement with the market to tackle the problem. </p>
<p>If stalls are caught selling illegal IPTV services and devices, in the first instance they receive a warning. If the activity continues, they can be fined, and if that does not solve the issue, tenants can lose their lease. </p>
<p>&#8220;Two tenants had their lease terminated in 2024 based on the agreements made,&#8221; BREIN writes, adding that &#8220;repeated checks and purchases at the Beverwijk Bazaar remain necessary to identify and deal with IPTV traders.&#8221;</p>
<h2>AI, NL and More</h2>
<p>In addition to the strong focus on IPTV, artificial intelligence is also flagged as a major threat. The group has identified several Dutch datasets that partly consist of copyright-infringing material and successfully <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/llm-taken-down-following-legal-pressure-from-anti-piracy-group-250128/">shut these down</a>. </p>
<p>&#8220;BREIN conducted extensive investigations into infringing datasets on which Generative AI models are trained and turned into unlawful AI models and was able to successfully complete the first AI investigations,&#8221; BREIN writes. </p>
<p>Another series of Dutch-focused achievements came after the registry for .NL domains updated its policy to no longer allow intermediaries to register domain names. The EURid registry (.eu) has a similar policy which enabled BREIN to make 16 .NL and 7 .EU domains <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/eu-and-nl-domain-registries-take-down-piracy-linked-domains-241220/">inaccessible</a>.  </p>
<p>These changes are part of broader efforts to involve more intermediaries in the anti-piracy fight. For example, BREIN says it signed a confidential agreement with several Dutch hosting providers who will enforce a proper know-your-customer policy. That could lead to more enforcement action in the future. </p>
<p>All in all, it&#8217;s been a productive year for BREIN. The <a href="https://stichtingbrein.nl/annual-report-2024/">full annual report</a> with more detail on specific actions and an overview of the key numbers, as summarized by BREIN, is available below. </p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>• 339 files closed<br />
• 179 investigations completed<br />
• 155 illegal sites/services/platforms stopped<br />
• 11 platforms, 9 IP addresses and 525 unique domains dynamically blocked at DNS level<br />
• 525 illegal websites completely removed from search results by Google iv<br />
• 160 proxies/mirrors stopped<br />
• 46 illegal traders IPTV/VOD subscriptions stopped<br />
• 14 IPTV ads removed by Google<br />
• 47 streaming sites taken offline<br />
• 3 major uploaders, administrators and/or scripters investigated and stopped<br />
• 166,945 Google search results removed<br />
• 3,677 interventions involving removal of online ads for illegal copies<br />
• 40 settlements, including 7 &#8216;knock &#038; talks&#8217;<br />
• 3 judicial ex parte orders obtained<br />
• 10 online cases involving physical media were handled<br />
• 14 checks conducted at record fairs<br />
• 16 .nl and 7 .eu domain names taken offline</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enders&#8217; Piracy Report Blames Big Tech; That&#8217;s What Anti-Piracy Lobbyists Do</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/enders-piracy-report-blames-big-tech-thats-what-anti-piracy-lobbyists-do-250602/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enders Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iptv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paywall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Premier League]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=268105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A new Enders Analysis report describes piracy of live sports and premium TV as "industrial scale theft" that costs companies such as Sky and the Premier League billions every year. The report calls out Amazon for selling legal Fire TV devices too cheaply, while Google and Microsoft receive criticism for lacking interest in DRM. These talking points show that Enders has its finger on the industry's pulse. Founded by a veteran anti-piracy lobbyist of more than 20 years, that's to be expected.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/record-piracy-s.png" alt="record-piracy" width="290" height="266" class="alignright size-full wp-image-243554" />If Hollywood studios, major record labels, broadcasters, and sports organizations stopped publishing their own piracy research, the scale of the phenomenon and potential solutions would likely be less clearly defined than they are today.</p>
<p>What we have instead is a largely unified response across multiple industries, featuring broadly similar claims on the scale of the problem, what needs to be done, and by whom. Everyone pushing in the same direction, no wasted energy.</p>
<p>The messaging is notable, not for just its clarity, but for the almost complete absence of conflicting opinions on who is to blame and how various goals can be achieved. It&#8217;s as if the dozens of major companies involved, many of them rivals operating in the same market, conducted their own independent research, arrived at the same conclusions, then brainstormed identical solutions totally independently.</p>
<h2>New Report, No Additional Friction</h2>
<p>A new report from Enders Analysis published on Friday was quickly covered by news outlets all over the world. Tackling the illegal streaming of live sports and premium TV, the report found that &#8220;industrial scale theft of video services&#8221; costs broadcasters and sports companies &#8220;billions&#8221; while posing a &#8220;direct threat&#8221; to the &#8220;UK creative industries.&#8221;</p>
<p>Company founder Claire Enders, CBE, told the Financial Times that “piracy is costing content originators, pay-TV and streaming companies, many billions globally,&#8221; a conclusion drawn from various data, including that provided by various European TV companies, such as Sky in the UK.</p>
<p>Impactful phrases of the type mentioned above are an immediately recognizable component of the anti-piracy vocabulary. After appearing in dozens of studies and countless press releases, over the years they may have lost some of their shock value. </p>
<p>At a time when the unstoppable proliferation of pirate services seems to be causing genuine problems, that&#8217;s certainly unfortunate. Nevertheless, contributors to these adverse conditions are called out in the report; they may even sound familiar.</p>
<h2>Video Piracy: Big Tech is Clearly Unwilling to Address the Problem</h2>
<p>The sub-heading above is the <a href="https://www.endersanalysis.com/reports/video-piracy-big-tech-clearly-unwilling-address-problem">title of the Ender&#8217;s report</a>, which signals its direction right from the start. Amazon, Google, and Microsoft are variously described as not doing enough to prevent piracy, or in the case of the former, actively fueling it as an &#8220;enabler&#8221;.</p>
<p>“Big tech is both friend and foe in solving the piracy problem. Conflicting incentives harm consumer safety by providing easy discovery of illegal pirated services, and reduced friction through low-cost hardware such as the Amazon Firestick,” the report notes.</p>
<p>The soaring popularity of Amazon&#8217;s devices was obvious <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/did-pirates-clean-out-amazon-fire-tv-stock-in-the-uk-151229/">almost 10 years ago</a> and thanks to a <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/amazons-evil-pirate-fire-stick-survives-18-months-of-free-viral-advertising-250302/">recent campaign</a>, unprecedented media coverage raised awareness of the Amazon brand, at zero cost to the company.</p>
<p>Enders&#8217; view of the &#8216;Firestick&#8217; issue was in part based on data provided by Sky, which found that 59% of pirates active in the previous 12 months using a physical device, said they had consumed pirated content via an Amazon Fire device. It&#8217;s an interesting statistic, some might even consider it an opportunity to be exploited. </p>
<p>Yet, if Amazon chooses not to respond in the manner the industry expects, there&#8217;s no legal Plan B available. Amazon doesn&#8217;t promote its products for infringing uses. It&#8217;s also a major rightsholder, not to mention member of both the MPA and Alliance for Creativity and Entertainment. Calling the company out in court as a piracy enabler isn&#8217;t just unrealistic, it&#8217;s much worse than that.</p>
<p>When a legal device is framed as a threat, not just by the video industry but also here in the Enders report, all that does is divert attention away from the core issues. Specifically, one of the main reasons that premium content from the UK is so readily available from pirate sources. According to the Enders report, Big Tech must take some responsibility for that too.</p>
<h2>Google and Microsoft Refuse to Engage on DRM</h2>
<p>Widevine and PlayReady, owned by Google and Microsoft respectively, are anti-piracy solutions that allow authorized users to view video streams while preventing downloading and unauthorized copies. Widely used to secure premium content, Widevine is used by major streaming services including Netflix, Amazon Prime, and Sky. But, after its weaknesses were exploited several years ago, protection from determined pirates isn&#8217;t what it used to be.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over twenty years since launch, the DRM solutions provided by Google and Microsoft are in steep decline,&#8221; the Engers report notes. </p>
<p>&#8220;A complete overhaul of the technology architecture, licensing, and support model is needed. Lack of engagement with content owners indicates this a low priority.&#8221;</p>
<p>Put more directly, it appears that Google and Microsoft have no interest in supporting or updating 26 and 18-year-old software/systems and, as a result, content pours rather than leaks out, fueling an entire pirate ecosystem. As quite literally the &#8216;source&#8217; of a significant part of the UK&#8217;s piracy problem, the Enders report quite rightly gives it a mention, although with framing clearly suggesting yet another Big Tech failure.</p>
<p>&#8220;The research by Enders Analysis accuses Amazon, Google, Meta and Microsoft of &#8216;ambivalence and inertia&#8217; over a problem it says costs broadcasters revenue and puts users at an increased risk of cyber-crime,&#8221; <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp3n7dx2174o">coverage</a> by the BBC reads.</p>
<p>That the Enders analysis views the piracy problem from the same long-standing positions of entertainment companies shouldn&#8217;t come as a surprise.</p>
<h2>A History of Championing Intellectual Property Rights</h2>
<p>Enders Analysis is known for its reports and generally speaking, receives praise for its work, in particular its focus on technology, telecoms and media. In 2009, founder Claire Enders told the Guardian that a prediction in 2001 that the music industry would have piracy under control by 2005, was a &#8220;Titanic&#8221; mistake. Yet, control was indeed being regained a few years later, leading to the record figures we see today and an industry in rude health.</p>
<p>How much of the credit for that can be attributed to Enders is hard to quantify, but her company&#8217;s position is clear, and as a staunch supporter of the UK&#8217;s Digital Economy Act, her personal position on piracy is <a href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201314/cmselect/cmcumeds/674/674we08.htm#footnote_2">extremely clear</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;It has been a decade since I first started to work for an industry-led anti-piracy regime, whose delay is detrimental to the creative economy,&#8221; Enders said at the time.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/enders-gov.png" alt="enders-gov" width="670" height="422" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268127" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/enders-gov.png 1005w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/enders-gov-300x189.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/enders-gov-600x378.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/enders-gov-150x94.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>That the report once again highlights the scale of piracy in the market isn&#8217;t a surprise, and importantly, isn&#8217;t inaccurate either. That Big Tech comes under fire for reasons identical to those of the affected industries, is no surprise either. Yet, it may be that when voices are so unified as one, there&#8217;s no opportunity for fresh ideas that might provide a solution, in the absence of Big Tech suddenly waving its magic wand.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, especially given its target audience and subscription model, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/755c9f71-4f10-4a18-a481-692cb4b250eb">an article in the Financial Times</a> covering the report has a mountain of comments from subscribers that may be quite useful. </p>
<p>The overwhelming majority see the piracy situation quite differently, but whether opposing views are welcome is another matter.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Most Pirated Movies of The Week – 06/02/2025</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/top-10-most-torrented-pirated-movies/</link>
					<comments>https://torrentfreak.com/top-10-most-torrented-pirated-movies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 23:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DVDrip]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=186926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Every week we take a close look at the most pirated movies on torrent sites. What are pirates downloading? 'Sinners' tops the chart, followed by 'A Minecraft Movie'. 'Fountain of Youth' completes the top three.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/sinners-300x188.jpg" alt="sinnars" width="300" height="188" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-268143" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/sinners-300x188.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/sinners-600x376.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/sinners-150x94.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/sinners.jpg 1114w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The data for our weekly download chart is estimated by TorrentFreak, and is for informational and educational reference only.</p>
<p>Downloading content without permission is copyright infringement. These torrent download statistics are only meant to provide further insight into piracy trends. All data are gathered from public resources. </p>
<p>This week we have no newcomers on the list. &#8220;Sinners&#8221; is the most shared title. </p>
<h2>The most torrented movies for the week ending on June 2 are:</h2>
<table class="css hover">
<thead>
<tr>
<th width="12%"><strong>Movie Rank</strong></th>
<th width="15%"><strong>Rank last week</strong></th>
<th><strong>Movie name</strong></th>
<th width="18%"><strong>IMDb Rating / Trailer</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tfoot>
<tr>
<td colspan="4">Most downloaded movies via torrent sites</td>
</tr>
</tfoot>
<p><body></p>
<tr>
<td><strong>1</strong></td>
<td>(5)</td>
<td>Sinners</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt31193180/">8.1</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bKGxHflevuk">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>2</strong></td>
<td>(1)</td>
<td>A Minecraft Movie</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3566834/">5.8</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8B1EtVPBSMw&#038;t=1s">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>3</strong></td>
<td>(3)</td>
<td>Fountain of Youth</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt27075958/">5,8</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1gB9h0ELEf0">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>4</strong></td>
<td>(7)</td>
<td>Captain America: Brave New World</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt14513804/">6.0</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1pHDWnXmK7Y">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>5</strong></td>
<td>(4)</td>
<td>Until Dawn</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt30955489/">5.9</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2b3vBaINZ7w">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>6</strong></td>
<td>(2)</td>
<td>Final Destination: Bloodlines</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9619824/">7.1</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UWMzKXsY9A4">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>7</strong></td>
<td>(6)</td>
<td>Snow White</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6208148/?">1.7</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iV46TJKL8cU">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>8</strong></td>
<td>(8)</td>
<td>Mickey 17</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt12299608/">7.0</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=osYpGSz_0i4">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>9</strong></td>
<td>(10)</td>
<td>Warfare</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt31434639/">7.5</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JER0Fkyy3tw">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>10</strong></td>
<td>(back)</td>
<td>A Working Man</td>
<td><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9150192/">5.7</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zTbgNC42Ops&#038;t=2s">trailer</a></td>
</tr>
<p></body></table>
<style>.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }</style>
<div class='embed-container'><iframe src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/bKGxHflevuk' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p>Note: We also publish an updating archive of all the list of <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/most-pirated-movies-of-2025/">weekly most torrented movies lists</a>.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://torrentfreak.com/top-10-most-torrented-pirated-movies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Record Labels and ISP Frontier Settle Piracy Liability Lawsuit</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/record-labels-and-isp-frontier-settle-piracy-liability-lawsuit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 20:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Repeat Infringer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frontier Communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repeat infringer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=268052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Several prominent record labels have settled their piracy liability lawsuit with Internet provider Frontier Communications. In a public notice, all parties agree to bear their own costs, but the details of the settlement agreement were not disclosed. The settlement arrives just weeks after a similar lawsuit filed by movie companies was settled ahead of trial. </p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pirate-flag-1.jpg" alt="pirate-flag" width="300" height="200" class="alignright size-full wp-image-194163" />In recent years, music and movie companies have filed several lawsuits against U.S. Internet providers, for failing to take action against pirating subscribers. </p>
<p>One of the main allegations is that the ISPs failed to terminate the accounts of repeat infringers in ‘appropriate circumstances’, as the DMCA requires.</p>
<p>These lawsuits resulted in multi-million-dollar judgments against Cox and Grande. Meanwhile, other companies remained at risk, including Frontier Communications which emerged from bankruptcy three years ago. </p>
<h2>Frontier Settles Twice</h2>
<p>Frontier was fighting not one, but two legal battles. The troubled company faced a pair of similar piracy liability lawsuits filed by movie and <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/record-labels-sue-frontier-for-failing-to-terminate-persistent-pirates-210609/">music companies</a>. Both cases were scheduled to go to trial this spring, but that didn&#8217;t happen. </p>
<p>Last month, we reported that the movie companies&#8217; lawsuit had been <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-site-blocking-demands-shelved-as-filmmakers-settle-with-u-s-isp-250428/">settled</a> on undisclosed terms. As a result, demands for pirate site blocking were also off the table.  </p>
<p>This week, the music companies, including UMG, Sony Music and Warner Music, also reached a settlement with Frontier. In a notice submitted to the New York federal court, they informed the court that all claims are settled and can therefore be dismissed. </p>
<p><center><em>Settled</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/settlenot.jpg" alt="settled" width="600" height="440" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-268063" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/settlenot.jpg 1204w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/settlenot-300x220.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/settlenot-600x440.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/settlenot-150x110.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<p>The case was settled &#8220;with prejudice&#8221; so the dismissed claims cannot be refiled in the future.  It&#8217;s a final resolution of the dispute, preventing all parties from bringing the same claims against each other again.</p>
<p>The settlement terms are not mentioned, so it&#8217;s unknown whether there was any financial compensation; however, when it comes to the court proceedings, all parties agreed to bear their own costs. </p>
<h2>Change Afoot?</h2>
<p>The settlement arrives in the same week the U.S. Government <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/u-s-govt-backs-cox-in-landmark-supreme-court-battle-over-isp-piracy-liability/">took a position</a> in a legal battle between Internet provider Cox and several record labels. The U.S. recommended the Supreme Court to hear Cox&#8217;s case, which seeks to overturn a liability ruling in favor of the music companies. </p>
<p>There is no reason to believe that the U.S. position impacted the Frontier lawsuit in any way. However, if the Supreme Court does indeed take on the matter, the eventual outcome will affect other piracy liability lawsuits against Internet providers. </p>
<p>Another recent development could also impact these cases. In the U.S., several lawmakers are working on site blocking legislation under which ISPs would be tasked with blocking access to pirate sites. According to recent information, some ISPs are open to this idea, provided they&#8217;re granted &#8220;<a href="https://torrentfreak.com/u-s-isps-want-retrospective-immunity-in-pirate-site-blocking-bill-250520/">retrospective immunity</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p>The details of these background discussions are sparse, but ISPs may not see the benefit in voluntarily working towards a blocking plan if they&#8217;re dealing with piracy liability lawsuits at the same time. </p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>A copy of the notice of settlement, submitted to the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York on Wednesday, is available here (pdf).</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IPTV Pirate Fights 25-30 Years Prison, &#8220;Facially Absurd&#8221; U.S. Govt Calculations</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/iptv-pirate-fights-25-30-years-prison-facially-absurd-u-s-govt-calculations-250530/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[IPTV and Streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iStreamitAll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jetflicks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kristopher Dallman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=268079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Five men found guilty of criminal copyright infringement in connection with pirate streaming site Jetflicks remain free after being convicted in 2024. In a sentencing memorandum filed at a Las Vegas court, counsel for group leader Kristopher Dallmann describes the government's loss calculations as "facially absurd" in a case featuring "an egregious incidence of the trial tax problem." The sentencing guideline range for Dallmann is an unprecedented 25 to 30 years.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/usdoj.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/usdoj.jpg" alt="Department of Justice" width="190" height="190" class="alignright size-full wp-image-91397" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/usdoj.jpg 190w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/usdoj-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 190px) 100vw, 190px" /></a>A complex case that had dragged on for years, in part due to the global pandemic, concluded last summer with the conviction of five men behind pirate streaming service Jetflicks.</p>
<p>The court heard that Kristopher Dallmann, Douglas Courson, Felipe Garcia, Jared Jaurequi and Peter Huber, generated millions of dollars in revenue through what was described as one of the largest pirate sites in the United States.</p>
<h2>The Case That Refuses to End</h2>
<p>Last summer, a <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/five-iptv-operators-guilty-of-movie-tv-piracy-leader-faces-48-years-in-prison-240621/">jury found all five men guilty </a>of conspiracy to commit criminal copyright infringement. Dallmann was further convicted on two counts of money laundering by concealment, plus three counts of misdemeanor criminal copyright infringement. No sentencing date was announced at the time, but the reported maximum sentences suggested that the defendants were in for a tough ride. </p>
<p>Four of the men were told they could receive up to 60 months in prison, but the Department of Justice highlighted that group leader Kristopher Dallmann could face a much higher sentence</p>
<p>The justification for this extraordinary estimate isn&#8217;t easily explained. The current docket has close to 700 filings and indictments that date back to 2019, for conduct that concluded in 2017. It&#8217;s a case in which two additional defendants pleaded guilty <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/jetflicks-programmer-of-pirate-iptv-service-handed-12-months-in-prison-210617/">six years ago</a>, one regarding conduct at Jetflicks, the other in connection with Jetflicks and rival streaming service, iStreamitAll.</p>
<h2>Argument Over Sentencing Continues</h2>
<p>Over the years, sealed filings regularly interrupted the flow of information, a trend that continues today, some 10 months after the defendants&#8217; convictions. None of the five men are currently incarcerated, and after fighting for every inch of ground for the last six years, Kristopher Dallmann isn&#8217;t ready to back down now.</p>
<p>In a supplemental sentencing memorandum dated last week, counsel for Dallmann contest the sentence proposed in the Presentence Investigations Report. Since access to the document is restricted, only limited details are available. However, language used by Dallmann&#8217;s counsel conveys a strong reaction to the government&#8217;s proposals, with an alternative sentencing proposition from the defense helping to establish a best-case scenario.</p>
<p>&#8220;Mr. Dallman respectfully asks that the Court to impose a sentence of one-year on the misdemeanor counts, 3 and 4, and a total sentence of thirty-six-months on the felony counts; each count running concurrent to each other,&#8221; the memorandum reads.</p>
<p>&#8220;This sentence is reasonable and &#8216;adequately reflects the seriousness of the offense, affords adequate deterrence, promotes respect for the law, provides just punishment for the offense, and protects the public.” </p>
<p>And then the teardown begins.</p>
<h2>Government&#8217;s Loss Calculations: &#8220;Facially Absurd&#8221;</h2>
<p>Counsel for Dallmann note that their primary focus is to dispute the PSR and the government&#8217;s infringement loss calculations, &#8220;which are, and this author does not say this lightly, facially absurd,&#8221; the submission notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Nor is the Office of Probation any help in conducting these calculations as that agency has relied solely on the government’s facially problematic, and unduly enigmatic, calculations.&#8221;</p>
<p>Describing the sentencing guideline calculations as &#8220;unresponsive to the actual facts of the case,&#8221; the defense says the draconian end result should give the court significant pause.</p>
<p>&#8220;The fundamental error of the infringement loss calculations is that, in addition to being almost comically speculative, it ignores the business model at issue. This case does not involve the retail purchase of individual television shows. At issue is a streaming service that the government alleges failed to acquire the proper reproduction licenses from the actual copyright holders.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Users of Jetflicks Were Not Victims</h2>
<p>The memorandum states that Jetflicks users can&#8217;t be classed as victims; they paid for a service and received one. The victims, &#8220;to the extent there are any,&#8221; are the copyright holders.</p>
<p>&#8220;The loss at issue is the licensing fee those holders would have received had Jetflicks acquired the right to stream from those entities. What this amount would have been, if the copyright holders would have even consented, is unknown and undeterminable. What is known is that the government’s loss calculations bear almost no resemblance to actual copyright holder losses.</p>
<p>&#8220;The problem with the calculations, lies in the government’s pedantic reliance on the concept of retail value when that concept applies to physical counterfeited items,&#8221; the defense argues. Again, no exact figures are provided but the defense says that the &#8220;government&#8217;s proffered infringement amount dwarfs, by a literal order of magnitude, the total gross receipts of Jetflicks over its entire lifespan.&#8221;</p>
<p>An attempt by the government to explain its calculations lacked reliance on case law, data, or expert analysis; &#8220;Indecipherable,&#8221; according to the defense. </p>
<p>&#8220;To the extent one can tell what the government is attempting to argue, it appears to be counting the same streaming content over and over again.&#8221; </p>
<h2>MPA Request for Attorney Fees</h2>
<p>Counsel for Dallmann highlight several points to explain why the MPA&#8217;s suggestion of attorney fees is &#8220;inappropriate.&#8221; Since the MPA is not a litigant in the case, it can&#8217;t be considered a prevailing party. There&#8217;s no itemized attorney bill to show costs directly related to the case, and there&#8217;s nothing to show which fees are permissible costs.</p>
<p>&#8220;If the MPA is the victim in this case, as it claims to represent all impacted copyright holders, that entity has made no effort to determine its losses. Instead, it relies on the government’s facially invalid loss theory,&#8221; the memorandum continues.</p>
<p>As far as any costs incurred while assisting the government&#8217;s prosecution, &#8220;those are not allowable losses as the costs of prosecuting a case are not recoverable as restitution.&#8221;</p>
<h2>The Trial Tax Problem</h2>
<p>In December 2019, Darryl Julius Polo (aka djppimp) pleaded guilty to charges of copyright infringement and money laundering for helping to program Jetflicks and for founding and operating rival platform iStreamitAll. Polo was sentenced to 57 months in prison, with a $1 million forfeiture order covering the proceeds of his offending.</p>
<p>According to Dallmann, the appearance of unproven allegations from Polo&#8217;s indictment in the PSR is problematic. Polo is described as a co-conspirator, whereas Dallmann maintains that Polo was a competitor operating a similar but entirely separate business. In practical terms the difference is important; as a co-conspirator, Dallmann can be held vicariously liable for Polo&#8217;s infringing business, in addition to conduct directly attributable to his own. </p>
<p>The U.S. government&#8217;s headline-grabbing description of Polo&#8217;s platform iStreamitAll contained a claim that it had a bigger library than Netflix, Hulu, Vudu, and Amazon Prime. That wasn&#8217;t necessarily a statement of fact, it was a claim copied from iStreamitAll&#8217;s sales pitch.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/doj-excerpt.png" alt="doj-excerpt" width="670" height="314" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268089" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/doj-excerpt.png 821w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/doj-excerpt-300x141.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/doj-excerpt-600x281.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/doj-excerpt-150x70.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>Nevertheless, it&#8217;s consistent with iStreamItAll offering a huge library of movies and TV shows, in contrast to Jetflicks which offered TV shows only. According to the defense, a comparison of the services and contrasting government-calculated infringement amounts, show that Dallmann is being punished more severely because he exercised his right to stand trial.</p>
<p>&#8220;The government represented in Polo’s signed plea agreement that the infringement amount under § 2B3.5 should be between $250,000 to $500,000. This calculation was based on the value of Mr. Polo’s inventory of infringement materials as found during the execution of search warrants,&#8221; the memorandum notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yet for Mr. Dallmann, because he failed to plead guilty, the government devised an entirely new way of calculating infringement value that increased the figure by literally more than a factor of sixty.&#8221; </p>
<p>The government-calculated figure in Dallmann&#8217;s case, presented in the still-restricted PSR, is $37,478,436.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/dallman-amount.png" alt="dallman-amount" width="670" height="206" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268091" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/dallman-amount.png 867w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/dallman-amount-300x92.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/dallman-amount-600x184.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/dallman-amount-150x46.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>&#8220;This is not a question of normal plea-bargaining concessions such as whether acceptance of responsibility reductions apply or whether the government would bring additional charges,&#8221; the memorandum continues. &#8220;This is a wholesale reformulation of a previously embraced sentencing theory. This raises the appearance, if not the specter, of undue retribution and punishment for the exercise of a constitutional right.&#8221;</p>
<p>Argument over calculations and various points of law continues for several pages but the easily missed bottom line, is the government&#8217;s position that Dallmann&#8217;s offending warrants the most severe sentence ever handed down in an online piracy case.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>The government’s conceptual corruption has resulted in a computed Sentencing Guideline range that is stunningly severe. It is reasonable to assert that a white-collar offender should not face a Sentencing Guideline range of twenty-five to thirty years for what is essentially a victimless crime; as the government has failed to show any actual victim losses.</p>
<p>The government’s theory dramatically increases the sentencing exposure of Mr. Dallmann. This conclusion is reinforced by looking to the calculations utilized for the co-defendants, such as Daryl Polo, where the infringement loss is approximately 1.5% of that advanced against Mr. Dallmann despite the fact the government describes Jetflicks and iStreamitAll as being similarly situated.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;Given Mr. Dallmann’s history and characteristics, which a host of mitigating factors as previously briefed under seal, a probationary sentence is warranted in this matter. If incarceration is deemed necessary by this Court, Mr. Dallmann respectfully asks this Court to consider a three-year sentence,&#8221; counsel for Dallmann conclude.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazil Advances Criminal Prosecution of American Yout.com Operator</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/brazil-advances-criminal-prosecution-of-american-yout-com-operator/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yout.com]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Popular stream-ripping site Yout.com has failed to have a criminal copyright complaint dismissed in Brazil. The prosecution will be allowed to continue its copyright claim against the American operator of the site, who faces a potential prison sentence. The court notes that the defense has strong arguments, but the burden of proof is low at this stage, so the case will proceed.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/yout-logo.jpg" alt="yout logo" width="300" height="172" class="alignright size-full wp-image-204776" />Over the past few years, stream-ripping service Yout.com has fought legal battles on several continents. </p>
<p>The most prominent lawsuit was filed by the site&#8217;s operator, American developer Johnathan Nader, who <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-sued-by-youtube-ripping-site-over-dmca-anti-circumvention-notices-201027/">took the RIAA to court</a> in an attempt to have the site declared legal.</p>
<h2>Criminal Prosecution</h2>
<p>The RIAA case is still under appeal and Yout.com remains available in most countries. Not in Brazil, however, as the site was effectively blocked several years ago after the Public Prosecutor’s Office of São Paulo, Brazil, <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/stream-ripping-site-yout-com-blocked-in-brazil-following-criminal-complaint-211124/">filed a criminal complaint</a>. </p>
<p>As part of the criminal proceeding, Yout.com was preemptively blocked by Brazilian ISPs. Unsurprisingly, this made the site&#8217;s traffic in the country tank. Perhaps even more concerning is a looming criminal sentence for the site&#8217;s American operator.</p>
<p>Nader doesn’t believe that his site is illegal, but if a Brazilian criminal court decides otherwise, criminal copyright infringement can result in a prison sentence of up to four years. Despite this pressure, Nader continues to stand behind the site. </p>
<h2>Deal Rejected</h2>
<p>In 2022, the prosecution offered Yout.com a way out in the form of a deal. In exchange for reaching an agreement on several predetermined terms, the public prosecutor was willing to suspend the criminal prosecution. This would come at a cost, however.</p>
<p>Under the proposed terms, Yout&#8217;s operator would have to pay the authorities 1.9 million Brazilian real, roughly $400,000, to be allocated to a special fund earmarked for social programs. </p>
<p>The deal also required Yout.com to actively block Brazilian visitors and delete their accounts, while ensuring all local payments were blocked. In addition, the site would have to log access attempts from Brazil and share the details with the authorities twice per month.</p>
<p>Nader and his legal team gave the proposal some serious thought, but eventually decided to decline the offer. Instead, they tried to turn the case in their favor through the court. </p>
<h2>Court Rejects Yout&#8217;s Motion to Dismiss</h2>
<p>In the 12th Criminal Court of the Central Criminal Court Barra Funda in São Paulo, the defense tried to have the complaint dismissed, citing a lack of just cause and insufficient evidence. The request was rejected earlier this month. </p>
<p>After reviewing arguments from both sides, the Court ruled that the prosecution&#8217;s criminal complaint is sufficient for the case to continue.</p>
<p>The prosecution alleges that Yout&#8217;s operator violated article 184, paragraph 3, of the Penal Code by offering an Internet-based tool to allow users to select and download a copyrighted work without obtaining permission from the rightsholder. This was allegedly motivated by profit. </p>
<p><center><em>From the order (translated)</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/sprul.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="127" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267941" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/sprul.jpg 1121w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/sprul-300x64.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/sprul-600x127.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/sprul-150x32.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<h2>Complaint Sufficient</h2>
<p>The Court found that the complaint meets the requirements of article 41 of the Code of Criminal Procedure.</p>
<p>&#8220;The indictment is based on minimal evidence, consisting of documents and expert reports, which, at this stage, are sufficient to support a judgment of admissibility. Although the defense presented strong arguments, it was unsuccessful in deconstructing the elements presented by the Public Prosecutor&#8217;s Office, and further evidence was required in the criminal investigation,&#8221; the order reads.</p>
<p>Yout typically describes itself as an Internet DVR. It does not store any copyright infringing material and does not know what files its users select to ‘format shift’.</p>
<p>However, the Court reiterated that the conditions for accepting a complaint concern evidence of authorship and materiality, not the full proof that will be developed during the investigation. Arguments about lack of evidence are not enough to reject the complaint at this initial phase.</p>
<p>&#8220;According to the consolidated understanding of the Supreme Courts, receiving a complaint only requires evidence of authorship and materiality, and does not require full proof, which will be produced during the investigation,&#8221; the order adds. </p>
<h2>Prosecution Goes Ahead</h2>
<p>Ultimately, the court concluded that the requirements for criminal prosecution are present and there are no defects that would warrant a dismissal under article 395 of the Code of Criminal Procedure. Therefore, the judge upheld the prior decision to accept the complaint.</p>
<p>The case will now move forward at a hearing set for August 9, 2025, for instruction, debates and judgment.</p>
<p>Since Nader lives in the United States, the hearing will be held virtually and won&#8217;t be required to appear in person. The prosecution is expected to present several witnesses, including a representative of the music industry.</p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>A copy of the (translated) order of the 12th Criminal Court of the Central Criminal Court in São Paulo is available <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/1028327-50.2021.8.26.0050-2-en.pdf">here (pdf)</a>.</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Employee Pleads Guilty in &#8220;Spider-Man&#8221; Pre-Release Piracy Case</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/employee-pleads-guilty-in-spider-man-pre-release-piracy-case/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 17:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pre-release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spider man]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A former employee of a disc manufacturing company in Memphis has signed a plea agreement, in which he admits stealing and distributing numerous DVD and Blu-ray discs. They include “Spider-Man: No Way Home,” which subsequently leaked online before its official release. As part of the agreement, the U.S. will recommend a relatively low sentence. </p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/piderm-600x382.jpg" alt="spider man" width="300" height="191" class="alignright size-large wp-image-268037" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/piderm-600x382.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/piderm-300x191.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/piderm-150x96.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/piderm.jpg 1106w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Three years ago, pirated Blu-ray copies of “Spider-Man: No Way Home” <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/spider-man-no-way-home-blu-ray-leaks-early-on-pirate-sites-220311/">began circulating</a> on pirate sites, weeks before its official release.</p>
<p>Such high-profile leaks are rare, and the source of the breach remained unknown until earlier this year.</p>
<p>In February, the U.S. Department of Justice <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/employee-charged-in-spider-man-pre-release-blu-ray-theft-linked-to-mass-piracy-250309/">indicted</a> 37-year-old Steven Hale from Tennessee, a former employee of a disc manufacturing and distribution company in Memphis. While working at the unnamed company between 2021 and 2022, Hale allegedly stole numerous “pre-release” DVD and Blu-ray discs from his employer.</p>
<p>These stolen discs contained many high-profile movie titles including &#8220;Spider-Man: No Way Home&#8221;.</p>
<h2>Hale Pleads Guilty</h2>
<p>Hale initially pleaded not guilty to two criminal copyright infringement charges and an additional charge of interstate transportation of stolen goods. This week Hale changed his plea, admitting guilt to one of the charges, and signing a plea agreement with the prosecution.</p>
<p>Hale entered his guilty plea to Count Two of the indictment. The charge relates to his distribution of ten or more copies of copyrighted works, including pre-release movies, for commercial advantage and private financial gain. This includes the pre-release &#8216;Spider-Man: No Way Home&#8217; disc, which is likely the source of the leak.</p>
<p>The other films covered by this count are &#8216;Jungle Cruise,&#8217; &#8216;Venom: Let There Be Carnage,&#8217; &#8216;Encanto,&#8217; &#8216;Eternals,&#8217; &#8216;The King’s Man,&#8217; &#8216;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings,&#8217; &#8216;Resident Evil: Welcome to Raccoon City,&#8217; &#8216;Marry Me,&#8217; &#8216;Sing 2,&#8217; and &#8216;The Matrix Resurrections.&#8217;</p>
<p><center><em>Plea Agreement</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pealagree.jpg" alt="plea agreemnet hale" width="600" height="353" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-268034" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pealagree.jpg 1112w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pealagree-300x176.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pealagree-600x353.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pealagree-150x88.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pealagree-220x130.jpg 220w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<h2>Lower Sentence, Limited Damages</h2>
<p>As part of the agreement, the prosecution agreed to drop two other counts and the Justice Department will recommend that the court awards the maximum available sentence reduction because Hale accepted responsibility. It will also recommend that the defendant is sentenced at the low end of the guideline range. </p>
<p>For the remaining count, Hale faces a potential maximum penalty of five years imprisonment, a $250,000 fine, and three years of supervised release. In addition, he has also agreed to pay restitution to all identifiable victims who suffered losses due to his criminal conduct.</p>
<p>Interestingly, for sentencing guideline purposes, the plea agreement puts the &#8220;infringement amount&#8221; between $15,000 and $40,000. That’s lower than the tens of millions of dollars in estimated losses mentioned in the indictment related to &#8216;Spider-Man: No Way Home. The final damages amount has yet to be determined by the court.</p>
<h2>1,160 Blu-rays and DVDs</h2>
<p>The plea agreement doesn&#8217;t add much detail to what is already publicly known. Importantly, however, it does reveal that law enforcement seized approximately 1,160 Blu-rays and DVDs from the defendant on or around March 14, 2022. </p>
<p>This means that the authorities had tracked down Hale as a potential suspect just days after the &#8216;Spider-Man&#8217; movie leaked online. After that, it took nearly three years before the defendant was indicted. </p>
<p>Why the indictment took so long is unknown, but the case may have been part of a broader ongoing investigation.</p>
<h2>Speculation and Sentencing</h2>
<p>While one can only speculate beyond this point, it is worth pointing out that the early online leaks of “Spider-Man: No Way Home” were shared publicly by the infamous release group EVO. This group was known for distributing pre-release content.</p>
<p>A few months after the authorities tracked down Hale, EVO was <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/authorities-arrested-leaders-of-prolific-piracy-release-group-evo-230315/">dismantled by the Portuguese authorities</a>. There is no evidence to suggest that these two cases are connected, but it&#8217;s not impossible either. </p>
<p>What we do know for sure is that Hale will be sentenced by the District Court of Tennessee later this year. This sentencing hearing is scheduled to take place at the end of August.</p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>A copy of the Plea Agreement, signed by all parties and submitted to the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Tennessee is <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/11347d9c-fe8a-43ff-9565-11a199c6ba2e-1.pdf">available here (pdf)</a>.</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pirate IPTV Consumed By 30% of Swedes, Including 50% of Men Under 35</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-iptv-consumed-by-30-of-swedes-including-50-of-men-under-35-290529/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 08:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Piracy Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iptv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mediavision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rattighetsalliansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rights Alliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweden]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The results of the latest consumer surveys, carried out by Mediavision in the Nordic countries, are a mixed bag of bad news, and slightly less bad news. On one hand, consumption of pirate IPTV services in Sweden has dropped two points, from 16% of all households in 2024 to 14% in 2025. On the other, 30% of over 15-year-olds consume content illegally every month, a figure that rises to over 50% among men under 35.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/swede-iptv1s.png" alt="swede-iptv1s" width="300" height="205" class="alignright size-full wp-image-268028" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/swede-iptv1s.png 500w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/swede-iptv1s-300x205.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/swede-iptv1s-150x103.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Describing Sweden as a country with a serious pirate IPTV problem is technically accurate, but lacking in all-important context.</p>
<p>As a member of the European Union, Sweden is among 27 member states experiencing broadly similar difficulties. The main drivers usually boil down to lots of content being accessible from one supplier, at a price people can afford or are willing to pay. </p>
<p>There are variables across the bloc, from consumer demand for specific types of often expensive regional content, to rightsholders&#8217; ability to take action, and/or convince local governments to commit scarce resources towards solving the problem.</p>
<p>In broad terms, the problem today is worse than it was pre-2020. No combination of industry measures, legal amendments, or government investment, has delivered anything close to a solution, anywhere in the EU. Even when positive news does arrive, it&#8217;s often met with cautious suspicion.</p>
<h2>60,000 Swedish Households Say &#8220;No&#8221; to IPTV</h2>
<p>Stockholm-based consulting firm Mediavision conducts regular surveys to assess consumption trends in the Nordic countries. Its report for Sweden covering several months in 2024 could hardly have been worse. </p>
<p>In the period bridging spring and the fall of last year, pirate IPTV subscription rates <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-iptv-sweden-mulls-viewing-ban-as-illegal-subscriptions-soar-25-250130/">increased by a record 25%</a>, with an estimated 700,000 households <em>(one subscription = one household)</em> regularly consuming from illicit sources. On face value, however, the numbers in Mediavision&#8217;s latest report seem to indicate progress.</p>
<p>&#8220;The use of illegal IPTV is still high and it is now estimated that 640,000 Swedish households pay for illegal IPTV services,&#8221; says anti-piracy group Rights Alliance (<a href="https://rattighetsalliansen.se/">Rattighetsalliansen</a>).</p>
<p>When a 60,000-household reduction warrants such a frosty reception (Rights Alliance says it&#8217;s too early to celebrate), the rest of the figures may not be encouraging either.</p>
<h2>2.3 Million Swedes Use Illegal Source Every Month</h2>
<p>The new Mediavision survey estimates that 2.3 million Swedes aged 15 to 74-years-old, consume movies, TV shows, or live sports, from illegal sources, at least every month. Sweden is a relatively small country where 2.3 million people represent 30% of the population considered in the survey.</p>
<p>Studies regularly show that infringement rates are higher among younger people; Sweden continues the long-standing trend here. </p>
<p>Among citizens aged 15 to 34, over half say they regularly use content from illegal sources. As expected, piracy rates are highest among younger men and when every other person is already a subscriber or regular viewer, word tends to spread especially fast.</p>
<h2>Organized Crime</h2>
<p>The Rights Alliance graphic below shows that another large number is also causing concern.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/rights-alliance-mediavision-2024.png" alt="rights alliance mediavision 2024" width="670" height="225" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-268029" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/rights-alliance-mediavision-2024.png 1132w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/rights-alliance-mediavision-2024-300x101.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/rights-alliance-mediavision-2024-600x201.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/rights-alliance-mediavision-2024-150x50.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>In 2019, the European Union Intellectual Property Office estimated that pirate IPTV services were generating close to a billion euros in annual revenue, in the EU alone <em>(<a href="https://euipo.europa.eu/tunnel-web/secure/webdav/guest/document_library/observatory/documents/reports/2019_Illegal_IPTV_in_the_European_Union/2019_Illegal_IPTV_in_the_European_Union_Full_en.pdf">pdf</a>)</em>. At the time, the Netherlands and Sweden had the highest percentage of IPTV users in the bloc, with 8.9% and 8.5% respectively. </p>
<p>To put Sweden&#8217;s pirate IPTV growth into perspective, today&#8217;s 640,000 households can be placed alongside 616,700 <em>individuals</em> in the six-year-old EU report. In 2018, revenue generated by pirate providers from Swedish sales was an estimated 490,000 euros.</p>
<p>The 1.4 billion figure above is in Swedish Krona; at today&#8217;s exchange rate that&#8217;s €137.6 million (US$154.8 million)</p>
<p>&#8220;1.4 billion SEK directly from Swedish households into the criminal economy is unacceptable. Organized crime is fueled, and the damages to rights holders are much bigger than this,&#8221; Rights Alliance says.</p>
<p>An investigation launched in Sweden a year ago is still ongoing. Alongside an assessment of financial damage to the film and TV industries, advice on whether action against IPTV subscribers is required (including a &#8216;ban&#8217; on IPTV itself) is expected in the final report. Rights Alliance believes that more can be done immediately.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a need for increased resources and enhanced expertise among police and prosecutors,&#8221; says Rights Alliance lawyer and former police IP crime investigator, Alma Shawwaf.</p>
<p>&#8220;Several actors can also do more to make it harder for criminals, not least payment providers and search engines such as Google.&#8221;</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Govt. Backs Cox in Landmark Supreme Court Battle Over ISP Piracy Liability</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/u-s-govt-backs-cox-in-landmark-supreme-court-battle-over-isp-piracy-liability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 14:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Repeat Infringer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cox Communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repeat infringer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Solicitor General has urged the Supreme Court to accept Cox Communications' petition in a landmark piracy liability lawsuit. The USSG argues that ISPs are not necessarily liable for pirating subscribers and warns that the current precedent may lead to disconnections for many innocent subscribers. At the same time, the USSG urged the court to deny a petition from the opposing music companies, which seeks to expand the current liability verdict.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/supremecourt.jpg" alt="supremecourt" width="300" height="248" class="alignright size-full wp-image-257709" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/supremecourt.jpg 1516w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/supremecourt-300x248.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In 2019, Internet provider Cox Communications lost its legal battle against a group of dozens of record labels, including Sony and Universal.</p>
<p>Following a two-week trial, a Virginia jury held Cox liable for its pirating subscribers. The ISP failed to disconnect repeat infringers and was ordered to pay <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/cox-is-liable-for-pirating-subscribers-hit-with-1-billion-damages-verdict-191220/">$1 billion in damages</a>.</p>
<p>This case is <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/category/lawsuits/repeat-infringer/">one of many</a>. Other ISPs have been accused of being similarly lax in their stance against alleged piracy. Rightsholders believe that ISPs are motivated by profit, while ISPs typically argue that they shouldn&#8217;t be held liable for the alleged wrongdoing of subscribers. </p>
<h2>Landmark Piracy Battle</h2>
<p>Cox challenged the verdict through <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/cox-appeals-billion-dollar-piracy-verdict-over-concealed-evidence-240528/">several routes</a> and last August filed a <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/cox-asks-supreme-court-to-protect-internet-subscribers-from-piracy-terminations-240815/">petition at the U.S. Supreme Court</a> asking it to hear the case. The Internet provider stressed that the current verdict &#8216;jeopardizes&#8217; internet access for all Americans. </p>
<p>Around the same time, the music companies filed <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/cox-asks-supreme-court-to-reject-record-labels-petition-over-isps-piracy-profits-241023/">their own petition</a>, hoping to strengthen the verdict at the Supreme Court. Specifically, the record labels argued that the ISP should also be held liable for vicarious copyright infringement.</p>
<p>Both petitions essentially boil down to questions on liability. Are ISPs liable for copyright infringement if they don&#8217;t disconnect subscribers accused of copyright infringement? And can ISPs be held liable for infringing subscribers, even if they don&#8217;t directly profit from their activities?</p>
<p>Last November, the Supreme Court suggested that it is indeed interested in the questions. Before deciding, however, the U.S. Solicitor General was invited to share the Government&#8217;s view on the matter. </p>
<p>The Solicitor General is a high-ranking official in the U.S. Department of Justice who serves as the federal government&#8217;s primary lawyer before the Supreme Court. Needless to say, their input weighs strongly for the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision whether to accept these petitions or not. </p>
<h2>U.S. Backs Cox&#8217;s Petition</h2>
<p>Yesterday, the Solicitor General submitted its amicus brief in this matter, clearly siding with the Internet provider. </p>
<p>The Solicitor General argues that the Fourth Circuit&#8217;s decision, which held Cox liable for contributory infringement, &#8220;departs from this Court&#8217;s contributory-infringement precedents&#8221;  and is in &#8220;substantial tension&#8221; with the Supreme Court&#8217;s recent analysis of secondary liability in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter,_Inc._v._Taamneh">Twitter v. Taamneh</a>. </p>
<p>&#8220;The Taamneh Court’s reasoning reinforces the conclusion that imposing liability on Cox for copyright infringement committed by its users, based on Cox’s failure to terminate service to IP addresses associated with infringement, is incompatible with traditional common-law limitations on secondary liability,&#8221; the brief reads.</p>
<p>The U.S. also cites the Sony and Grokster cases, which make clear that contributory liability for copyright infringement requires more than knowing about pirating activity. Instead, it requires “culpable intent” to cause copyright infringement.</p>
<p>&#8220;If Cox had explicitly or implicitly marketed its service as being particularly useful for infringers, or if it had encouraged subscribers to use Cox’s internet service to infringe, liability might be appropriate,&#8221; the Solicitor General writes. </p>
<p>According to the view of the U.S. Government, an ISP is not automatically liable for copyright infringement if it fails to terminate subscribers after receiving copyright infringement notices. This is a strong statement that targets the central issue in many similar lawsuits in U.S. courts.</p>
<p><center><em>Not Liable</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/notliable.jpg" alt="not liable" width="600" height="370" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267999" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/notliable.jpg 1734w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/notliable-300x185.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/notliable-600x370.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/notliable-150x92.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/notliable-1536x946.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center> </p>
<h2>Innocent Subscribers at Risk</h2>
<p>The amicus brief goes on to state that the current verdict of the Court of Appeals can have broad implications for ISPs and their subscribers. </p>
<p>Cox previously argued that, based on this precedent, ISPs find themselves ‘forced’ to terminate subscribers who may have done little wrong. The U.S. Solicitor General acknowledges this potential threat.</p>
<p>If copyright infringement notices from third parties can trigger liability, Internet providers may take more drastic action to avoid legal trouble.</p>
<p>&#8220;Given the breadth of that liability, the decision below might encourage providers to avoid substantial monetary liability by terminating subscribers after receiving a single notice of alleged infringement,&#8221; the Solicitor General writes. </p>
<p>&#8220;Losing internet access is a serious consequence, as the internet has become an essential feature of modern life. And because a single internet connection might be used by an entire family—or, in the case of coffee shops, hospitals, universities, and the like, by hundreds of downstream users— the decision below could cause numerous non-infringing users to lose their internet access.&#8221;</p>
<h2>No Willful Infringement</h2>
<p>Aside from the liability question, the brief also criticizes the Fourth Circuit&#8217;s finding of &#8220;willfulness&#8221; against Cox, which led to the enhanced statutory damages. </p>
<p>The Solicitor General argues that the jury instruction was &#8220;erroneous&#8221; because it allowed a finding of willfulness based on the notion that Cox knew its subscribers&#8217; actions were unlawful, even though Cox believed its own response was lawful. </p>
<p>The Solicitor General notes that &#8220;willfulness&#8221; generally requires knowledge or reckless disregard that the defendant&#8217;s own conduct was unlawful. Simply knowing about third-party infringements should not be sufficient.</p>
<p>This broad interpretation would essentially undermine the Copyright Act&#8217;s two-tiered damages scheme, which reserves higher damages for willful copyright infringement than for non-willful infringement. </p>
<h2>Music Companies&#8217; Writ Should be Denied</h2>
<p>While the U.S. supports Cox&#8217;s petition, it has asked the Supreme Court to deny a related writ from the opposing music labels, who argue that Cox should also be held liable for vicarious copyright infringement.</p>
<p>Defendants can be held vicariously liable if they had the right and ability to control the infringing activities and a direct financial interest in those activities. According to the Solicitor General, the lower court correctly concluded that is not the case here.</p>
<p>&#8220;There was no evidence that Cox would be forced to collect a lower fee if the users of its internet service ceased to infringe; that subscribers were drawn to Cox’s internet service because of the ability to engage in copyright infringement using that service; or that Cox had used the opportunity for customers to infringe to lend credibility to the service it offered,&#8221; the brief notes. </p>
<p>All in all, it&#8217;s clear that the U.S. Solicitor General, and thus the U.S. Department of Justice, supports Cox&#8217;s attempt to overturn the piracy liability verdict. While the Supreme Court has yet to formally decide whether it will take on the case, the brief suggests the chance is now significantly higher. </p>
<p><center><em>Conclusion</em></center><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/grantcur.jpg" alt="grant" width="600" height="332" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-268011" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/grantcur.jpg 1760w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/grantcur-300x166.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/grantcur-600x332.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/grantcur-150x83.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/grantcur-1536x850.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /> </p>
<p>While Cox will be pleased to see the supportive brief, there are no guarantees that the Supreme Court will agree with the U.S. Solicitor General, should it ultimately decide to take on the case. </p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p><strong><em>Update:</em></strong> After publication, Cox spokesperson Todd Smith sent us the following statement.</p>
<p>“We are pleased the Solicitor General agrees the Supreme Court should review this significant copyright case that could jeopardize internet access for all Americans and fundamentally change how internet service providers manage their networks. Cox knows how critical reliable broadband services are for the communities we serve.”</p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>A copy of the U.S. Solicitor General&#8217;s Amicus Curiae brief for the United States is available <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/20250527172838692_Cox-Sony.CVSG_.pdf">here (pdf)</a>.</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LaLiga&#8217;s &#8220;Precise&#8221; Blocking Cut Piracy By 40-60%, &#8220;Without Collateral Impact&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/laliga-says-blocking-cut-piracy-by-40-60-focused-precise-without-collateral-impact-250528/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 07:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Site Blocking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iptv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javier Tebas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LaLiga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overblocking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[site blocking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After months of unprecedented site-blocking controversy, LaLiga informs TorrentFreak that piracy decreased by 40% at weekends and as much as 60% for a hotly-anticipated matchup. Yet interestingly, LaLiga's view of the nationwide overblocking crisis sits in stark contrast to reports published elsewhere. Primarily, there's no hard evidence that a crisis even exists; total formal complaints received by LaLiga in its dedicated inbox: zero.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2.png" alt="" width="300" height="152" class="alignright size-full wp-image-267853" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2.png 500w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2-300x152.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2-150x76.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />When rightsholders, broadcasters, and ISPs have a shared interest in the success of a multi-billion euro broadcasting rights deal, there&#8217;s no dispute over the need for a blocking order. </p>
<p>With formalities out of the way, who argues against asking the court for anything less than the full measures the judge is prepared to authorize?</p>
<p>When Telefonica spent billions acquiring broadcasting rights from LaLiga, the companies received <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/did-a-court-really-authorize-internet-service-providers-to-block-cloudflare-250223/">full backing</a> from ISPs/TV providers to protect their collective revenues. According to LaLiga&#8217;s reading of the piracy blocking order subsequently obtained from the court, it authorizes the applicants to take whatever blocking actions are necessary to prevent access in Spain to around 130 pirate sites.</p>
<p>That many of the sites used Cloudflare IP addresses, each shared among hundreds or thousands of sites with no connection to piracy, came as no surprise to the applicants. Unlike blocking orders obtained outside Spain where similar issues are dealt with differently, LaLiga began instructing ISPs to block Cloudflare IP addresses used by pirate sites listed in the order.</p>
<h2>Outlawed By Some Courts, Unprecedented Blocking Ensued</h2>
<p>Some estimates claim that over two million innocent sites were affected by blocking but whatever the true number, the decision to block Cloudflare at scale was unprecedented. </p>
<p>LaLiga&#8217;s claim, that the injunction authorizes blocking of Cloudflare IP addresses, seems to be confirmed by the text of the order. It&#8217;s only when attempting to reconcile LaLiga&#8217;s intellectual property rights with the general and indeed fundamental rights of third parties does the situation become unfathomable. So we asked LaLiga about something else instead.</p>
<p>Since everyone seems to be on the same page concerning the blocking of shared IP addresses, we put it to LaLiga that when compared to site-blocking measures that aim to avoid collateral damage (most blocking worldwide), knowingly &#8216;overblocking&#8217; must introduce new risks. Did LaLiga conduct a risk assessment before it started to block Cloudflare in February?</p>
<p>&#8220;At LALIGA we are fully aware that any blocking measure —even when legally justified— requires a cautious and proportional approach,&#8221; the league responded.</p>
<p>&#8220;That is precisely why we do not act indiscriminately, and why all our blocking actions are backed by judicial resolutions that assess the proportionality and potential impact before being authorized. It&#8217;s relevant to highlight that these blockings are requested and implemented once there are clear proofs of piracy signals and content.&#8221;</p>
<h2>The Importance of Definitions</h2>
<p>LaLiga&#8217;s position as stated here appears to stand on its definition of <em>proportional</em>, <em>indiscriminate</em>, and its grounds for blocking. It seems safe to assume that the IP addresses it reports are indeed being used by pirate sites offering its content illegally. Grounds for blocking don&#8217;t get any better than that.</p>
<p>If we place a tight definition on the word <em>indiscriminate</em>, it&#8217;s reasonable to assume that the IP addresses identified by LaLiga are obtained scientifically rather than randomly pulled out of hat. So with indiscriminate set the side for a moment, we have ourselves a question.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>When a rights holder with legal standing demonstrates a genuine need to block, has obtained authorization from a court, and has no other immediate options available:</em></p>
<p><em>Does a proportional approach to infringement include blocking an IP address when there&#8217;s a risk that dozens, hundreds, or thousands of innocent third parties are using it too?</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Herein lies an even bigger problem, directly linked to the biggest question of all.</p>
<h2>Does TV Subscription Data Reveal Any Positive Effects of Blocking?</h2>
<p>Establishing whether blocking has a positive effect on sales often prompts charts showing fewer people visiting blocked sites. Data cited by CEO Javier Tebas indicates that blocking suppressed piracy on a grand scale.</p>
<p>&#8220;Weekend piracy has decreased by 40%. That doesn&#8217;t mean everyone has already switched to paid channels, but&#8230; how do we know this? Barcelona-Inter semifinal in Spain: 1,200,000 viewers and a certain amount of data usage. El Clásico, four days later, had a much larger audience—two million—and resulted in 60% less piracy in consumption. In other words, it made a difference: more viewers were seen, much less illegal consumption as a result of the blocks we&#8217;re implementing,” he explains.</p>
<p>If this is an accurate picture, it&#8217;s not unreasonable to conclude that such large percentages are likely to have some impact on Spanish football&#8217;s bottom line. The immediate problem concerns the type of blocking used to achieve these results and whether similar authority would be granted again.</p>
<p>That leads to another complication.</p>
<h2>No Evidence to Show Overblocking</h2>
<p>Back in March when <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/cloudflare-asks-court-to-end-laligas-illegal-blocking-response-to-encrypted-client-hello-250220/">Cloudflare</a> and RootedCON separately attended court hoping to end LaLiga&#8217;s ability to block, <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/judge-confirms-laligas-right-to-block-cloudflare-in-pursuit-of-iptv-pirates-250328/">neither was successful</a>, in part due to evidential failures. In short, information presented to the court was deemed insufficient since it failed to show &#8220;specific, quantifiable damage to third parties.&#8221; It&#8217;s a theme that still interests LaLiga.</p>
<p>&#8220;LALIGA has implemented a dedicated mailbox for complaints related to the blocking measures. This mechanism allows any third party who believes they’ve been unintentionally affected by a blocking action to contact us directly, provide technical evidence, and request a review,&#8221; Laliga says.</p>
<p>&#8220;To date, we have not received any formal complaints through this channel nor received any formal complaint through other legal channels, which reinforces our position that the system is working as intended: focused, precise, and without collateral impact on legitimate services.&#8221;</p>
<p>At Soccerex Amsterdam last weekend, Javier Tebas said that while LaLiga&#8217;s critics describe the court order as &#8220;useless&#8221; and &#8220;make a lot of noise,&#8221; it&#8217;s an example of what can be done.</p>
<p>[The order is] dynamic and should be implemented country by country. It&#8217;s very important that rights holders, UEFA, and national leagues become more united and more convinced that this is the way forward.”</p>
<p><em>The controversial order is available <a href="https://www.poderjudicial.es/search/AN/openDocument/766326fb999ba14aa0a8778d75e36f0d/20250331">here</a> (pdf, Spanish)</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Musi Alleges Apple’s App Store Removal Was Orchestrated, Seeks Sanctions</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/musi-alleges-apples-app-store-removal-was-orchestrated-seeks-sanctions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 12:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps and Sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The legal dispute between Apple and music streaming app Musi has taken another unexpected turn. Following Apple's motion for sanctions, which dismissed Musi's allegations that a backroom deal was responsible for the app's removal, Musi has countered with a detailed overview of communications between Apple, YouTube, and music industry officials, while also calling for sanctions. </p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/musilogo.jpg" alt="musi logo" width="300" height="192" class="alignright size-full wp-image-258144" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/musilogo.jpg 766w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/musilogo-300x192.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/musilogo-600x383.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/musilogo-150x96.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Last September, <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/apple-removes-parasitic-streaming-app-musi-following-persistent-complaints-240926/">Apple removed</a> the popular music streaming app Musi from its App Store, affecting millions of users. </p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s action wasn&#8217;t completely unexpected. Music industry groups had been trying to take Musi down for a long time, <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/music-industry-puts-pressure-on-parasitic-streaming-app-musi-240726/">branding it a &#8216;parasitic&#8217; app</a> that skirts the rules.</p>
<h2>Musi Sues Apple</h2>
<p>Delisting from the App Store put the future of Musi directly at risk. The company initially hoped to resolve the matter with Apple behind closed doors, but since the tech giant was unwilling to reverse its decision, Musi took the matter to court.</p>
<p>Musi claimed that the App Store removal was the result of &#8220;backroom conversations&#8221; between Apple and key music industry players. The app developer alleged this was an &#8220;unfair&#8221; and &#8220;tainted&#8221; removal process designed to put it out of business.</p>
<p>Musi requested a preliminary injunction to reinstate the app, but that attempt failed. In January, a California federal court denied the injunction, ruling that Apple did not act unreasonably or in bad faith when it removed the app following complaints from music industry players and YouTube. </p>
<h2>Apple Calls for Sanctions</h2>
<p>With the underlying lawsuit yet to be resolved, a few weeks ago Apple fired back with a motion for sanctions. According to Apple, the court should sanction Musi for false or misleading allegations, which include the remarks concerning the alleged “backchannel scheme”.</p>
<p>According to Apple, discovery in this case clearly revealed that there were no backroom deals but Musi nonetheless included these claims in its amended complaint.</p>
<p>“[D]iscovery thoroughly disproved Musi’s baseless conspiracy theory that Apple schemed to eliminate the Musi app from the App Store to benefit ‘friends’ in the music industry,” Apple notes. </p>
<p>Apple further alleged that to get its app reinstated after an earlier removal years ago, Musi allegedly faked an UMG email. These alleged misrepresentations are sanctionable, Apple argues, while reiterating that it had received numerous complaints about Musi from various parties over the years.</p>
<h2>Musi Fires Back, Requests Sanctions</h2>
<p>Last week, Musi responded in court by opposing Apple&#8217;s motion and, in turn, requesting sanctions against Apple. The app creator notes that sanctions motions are often used as a tactic of intimidation and harassment and describes Apple’s motion as &#8220;a member of that shameful lineage.&#8221;</p>
<p><center><em>From Musi&#8217;s motion</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-scaled.jpg" alt="musi motion" width="600" height="131" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267889" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-scaled.jpg 2400w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-300x65.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-600x131.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-150x33.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-1536x335.jpg 1536w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/intoharaas-2048x447.jpg 2048w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<p>A motion for sanctions is warranted if there are no facts to support the allegations but Musi contends that its claims are supported by credible evidence obtained during discovery.</p>
<p>&#8220;None of Musi’s challenged allegations are factually baseless, and all are based on a reasonable and competent inquiry by Musi’s counsel. Apple’s motion should thus be denied, and Apple should itself be sanctioned and required to pay Musi’s attorneys’ fees for opposing its baseless motion.&#8221;</p>
<h2>&#8216;Not a Simple App Removal&#8217;</h2>
<p>Apple previously argued that there was no need for backroom discussions as Apple could simply remove Musi under its own terms, with or without previous complaints from rightsholders. Musi doesn&#8217;t deny that, but it notes that evidence indicates this isn&#8217;t what happened.</p>
<p>Based on evidence gathered through discovery, Musi suggests that there were ongoing discussions behind the scenes to discuss the potential removal of the app. The timeline below reflects <em>Musi&#8217;s perspective and interpretation</em> of these events.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8211; April 11, 2024: A Sony Music Entertainment executive, Jeff Walker, emails senior Apple legal personnel (Elizabeth Miles and Robert Windom) requesting Apple&#8217;s assistance in removing the Musi app from the App Store. Specifically, Sony asked for help to &#8220;identify a path forward&#8221; to &#8220;have the Musi app removed from the Apple app store&#8221;.</em></p></blockquote>
<p><center><em>A Path Forward</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward.jpg" alt="a path forward" width="600" height="268" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267891" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward.jpg 2141w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward-300x134.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward-600x268.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward-150x67.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward-1536x686.jpg 1536w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pathforward-2048x914.jpg 2048w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<blockquote><p>
<em>&#8211; May 20, 2024: Apple&#8217;s Elizabeth Miles holds a call with Sony&#8217;s Jeff Walker about the Musi app, at Sony&#8217;s request.</p>
<p>&#8211; May 24, 2024: Following internal Apple discussions, Apple&#8217;s Chief Counsel of Content and Services, Robert Windom, instructs Apple in-house counsel Sean Cameron to &#8220;please try to get that meeting set up&#8221;. Musi implies that this was a meeting with YouTube.</p>
<p>&#8211; Around May 29, 2024: At Cameron&#8217;s direction, Apple&#8217;s YouTube liaison, Arun Singh, contacts YouTube&#8217;s Kelvin Paulino by phone. Musi argues Singh inquired about a March 2023 YouTube complaint that Apple had previously considered &#8220;resolved&#8221;; Singh testified Paulino initially seemed unaware of Musi or the complaint.</p>
<p>&#8211; July 15, 2024: The Call: Apple and YouTube legal teams meet. According to Musi (citing Apple&#8217;s own witnesses), Apple counsel Sean Cameron stated Apple considered YouTube&#8217;s 2023 complaint &#8220;resolved&#8221; and, after mentioning other &#8220;music industry&#8221; complaints, asked YouTube if it wanted to &#8220;continue with the [2023] complaint&#8221;. YouTube allegedly confirmed ongoing API violations by Musi and expressed intent to pursue the complaint, requesting Apple send an email to formalize this.</p>
<p>&#8211; The &#8220;Re-Open&#8221; Email: Post-call, Apple&#8217;s &#8216;AppStoreNotices&#8217; emailed YouTube Legal: &#8220;Per request from the YouTube Legal team&#8230; If you would like to re-open your claim against this app, please specify the rights you believe are being infringed&#8230;&#8221;.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><center><em>Re-Open</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen.jpg" alt="the reopen email" width="600" height="414" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267893" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen.jpg 2104w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen-300x207.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen-600x414.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen-150x104.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen-1536x1061.jpg 1536w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/reopen-2048x1414.jpg 2048w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8211; August 20, 2024: Apple&#8217;s Elizabeth Miles has a call with National Music Publishers Association (NMPA) representatives regarding Musi, at the NMPA&#8217;s request.</p>
<p>&#8211; September 11, 2024: The NMPA sends Apple a letter supporting YouTube&#8217;s complaint against Musi.</em></p></blockquote>
<h2>Turning the Tables</h2>
<p>Musi believes this is sufficient to back up its claim that the app&#8217;s removal was the result of “backroom conversations” between Apple and key music industry players. In any case, it argues that a motion for sanctions is not warranted, as this wasn&#8217;t a simple removal process. </p>
<p>To strengthen its claim, Musi cites an email from Apple&#8217;s Elizabeth Miles who, after Musi was removed, noted that it was a &#8220;complex process&#8221;.</p>
<p><center>Complex process</center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex.jpg" alt="complex" width="600" height="247" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267896" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex.jpg 2060w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex-300x124.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex-600x247.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex-150x62.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex-1536x633.jpg 1536w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/complex-2048x844.jpg 2048w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<p>According to Musi, Apple&#8217;s motion for sanctions is baseless and should therefore be denied. Turning the tables, the app devloper asked the court to sanction Apple for improper use of a sanctions motion. </p>
<p><em>&#8212;</p>
<p>A copy of Musi&#8217;s opposition to Apple&#8217;s motion for sanctions, filed at the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California, is <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/musi-reply-1.pdf">available here (pdf)</a></em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Portugal Remains a Piracy Hotspot Despite Blocking Thousands of Sites</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/portugal-remains-a-piracy-hotspot-despite-blocking-thousands-of-sites/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 20:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Site Blocking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msuo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portugal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[site blocking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Portugal often served as an example of how effectively pirate site blocking measures can be implemented. Internet providers are blocking more than 3,000 domain names today with relative ease. While Hollywood reported that the blocks are effective, not all rightsholders necessarily agree. In fact, new data reveals that Portugal remains a piracy hotspot in Europe.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/portugal-flag-600x472.jpg" alt="portugal flag" width="300" height="236" class="alignright size-large wp-image-267684" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/portugal-flag-600x472.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/portugal-flag-300x236.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/portugal-flag-150x118.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/portugal-flag.jpg 951w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Portugal now has a decade of experience with pirate site blocking measures, which were made possible through a voluntary agreement</p>
<p>In 2015, the country&#8217;s blocking scheme was formalized through a deal between several parties, including the Government, rightsholders, and Internet providers.</p>
<p>Under the blocking regime, many thousands of domain names have been blocked over the years. To strengthen the impact, advertisers joined in on the action by preventing ad placements on these sites. </p>
<h2>Portugal: A Leading Site Blocking Example</h2>
<p>The relative ease of this rollout, which received little pushback overall, was swiftly embraced by Hollywood. In 2016, Portugal served as a <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/mpaa-says-portugals-pirate-site-blocking-system-is-world-leader-161007/">leading example</a> of how other countries, including Spain and France, could implement their blocking plans. </p>
<p>A year later, a Hollywood-commissioned study <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/portugals-pirate-site-blocking-system-works-great-study-shows-170728/">confirmed</a> that traffic to blocked sites had decreased significantly. This shouldn’t really come as a surprise, as these domains are blocked after all, but it was seen as a great accomplishment nonetheless. </p>
<p>While site blocking is effective at blocking specific domains, it typically boosts traffic to unblocked sites. The effect wasn&#8217;t considered in the initial study, but the problem was <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/censoring-pirate-sites-is-counterproductive-research-finds-160708/">previously documented</a> in related research. And it&#8217;s visible today too, as Portugal&#8217;s piracy woes are far from over.  </p>
<h2>Blocking Pioneer <em>and</em> Piracy Hotspot?</h2>
<p>Earlier this year, Apritel, the association for Portuguese Internet providers and telcos, flagged pirate streaming and IPTV services as a major problem. The group didn&#8217;t mention blocking as a solution, but suggested that the authorities should enable <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/piracy-blocks-dont-work-portuguese-telcos-now-call-for-sanctions-against-users-250430/">financial penalties</a> for users of these services.</p>
<p>These piracy concerns are shared by many rightsholders and were also a topic at the <a href="https://www.igac.gov.pt/w/iii-coloquio-internacional-sobre-pirataria-de-conteudos-digitais">Colloquium on Digital Piracy of Audiovisual Content</a>, which took place in Lisbon last week. Here, many stakeholders discussed the ongoing piracy challenges. </p>
<p>With more than 3,000 blocked domain names, Portugal has strict anti-piracy measures in place. However, data from piracy tracking firm <a href="https://www.muso.com/">MUSO</a>, prepared for last week’s meeting, shows that piracy remains popular in Portugal, even by European standards.</p>
<p>&#8220;Portugal&#8217;s piracy rate per user is 33% higher than the European average, marking it as one of the most active territories for unauthorised content consumption,&#8221; MUSO <a href="https://www.muso.com/magazine/portugals-piracy-rates-surpass-european-average">explains</a>. </p>
<p>The higher piracy rates are also reflected in the number of visits to pirate sites by Internet users. These visit numbers are higher than in any other country in the region, despite the existing blocking measures. </p>
<p>&#8220;This pattern of high engagement has remained consistent across several years, indicating a need for ongoing and more refined enforcement strategies,&#8221; MUSO <a href="https://www.muso.com/magazine/portugals-piracy-rates-surpass-european-average">writes</a>, aligning with the call for stronger enforcement. </p>
<p>Since MUSO only reports data on website visits, the growth in the use of pirate IPTV services is not reflected in these numbers. Instead, it appears that Portugal&#8217;s piracy numbers are in large part due to a seemingly overlooked content category.</p>
<h2>Manga / Anime Blindspot?</h2>
<p>After years of site blocking, many pirate sites are known to temporarily evade measures by switching to new domain names, which are eventually blocked again, resulting in an ongoing cat and mouse game. Tugaflix, for example, has been blocked for a decade, but new domains continue to show up. </p>
<p>MUSO data shows that a &#8216;Tugaflix&#8217; domain has appeared in the list of ten most visited pirate sites in Portugal over the past 12 months. The domain has since been blocked and has already moved to a new location.</p>
<p><center><em>Pirate sites with most visits (MUSO: April 24 / March 25)</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/porpirate.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="399" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267703" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/porpirate.jpg 815w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/porpirate-300x266.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/porpirate-600x532.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/porpirate-150x133.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></center></p>
<p>The list also reveals another interesting insight. The list of most visited piracy sites includes many Manga and Anime sites, including the hugely popular Asuracomic.net, as well as Hianime and 3xyaoi. According to our blocklist data, these remain accessible in Portugal. </p>
<p>In fact, we don&#8217;t see any Manga or Anime related website in the list of <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/domains-blocked-portugal.png">3,000 blocked domain names</a> we have access to, which was updated a few months ago. Apparently, this is somewhat of an enforcement blindspot. </p>
<p>This means that the relatively high piracy rates are not necessarily the result of lacking anti-piracy measures. Online piracy doesn&#8217;t magically disappear merely because anti-piracy tools exist; these tools must be actively and properly utilized by rightsholders. </p>
<p>Whether this was also a topic of discussion at last week&#8217;s anti-piracy colloquium is unknown. </p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cloudflare CEO: Football Piracy Blocks Will Claim Lives; &#8220;I Pray No One Dies&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/cloudflare-ceo-football-piracy-blocks-will-claim-lives-i-pray-no-one-dies-250526/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 06:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloudflare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javier Tebas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LaLiga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matthew prince]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cloudflare CEO Matthew Prince issued a stark warning over LaLiga's ISP blocking campaign. The blockades deny access to less than 150 pirate sites and reportedly render millions of innocent websites unavailable. Prince said he "prays no one dies," after revealing Spanish citizens are being denied access to critical resources. Mass blocking of Cloudflare continued on Sunday, despite a clear indication from Prince that his company has always been willing to cooperate.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2.png" alt="cloudflare-spain-s2" width="300" height="152" class="alignright size-full wp-image-267853" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2.png 500w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2-300x152.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/cloudflare-spain-s2-150x76.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LaLiga&#8217;s 2024/2025 season is officially over. FC Barcelona were actually crowned champions on Thursday after it became mathematically impossible for Real Madrid to conjure up seven points or more from the six points available.</p>
<p>The final matches of the season were played on Sunday but with the championship settled, would LaLiga show restraint and taper down its blocking activity? Or perhaps it would continue under the authority of judge, despite the widespread collateral damage inflicted on innocent internet users since February, a scandal now known as #laligagate.</p>
<h2>In For a Penny?</h2>
<p>The early signs did little to inspire confidence. Protest website LaLigaGate.com was hit by a total blockade but whether the site was targeted deliberately or succumbed to collateral damage is unknown.</p>
<p><center><em>Intentional and Unintentional Blocking Look Identical</em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/laligagate-down.png" alt="laligagate-down" width="670" height="366" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267855" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/laligagate-down.png 735w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laligagate-down-300x164.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laligagate-down-600x328.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laligagate-down-150x82.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>As the <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/constitutional-court-urged-to-end-piracy-blockades-now-hurting-millions-250519/">latest data</a> suggests that mass blocking of Cloudflare in pursuit of 150 piracy platforms has negatively affected millions of innocent websites, use of the term &#8216;collateral damage&#8217; may be running out of scope. </p>
<p>Unintentional overblocking became inevitable overblocking some time ago, a point certainly not lost on Cloudflare CEO Matthew Prince.</p>
<p>Posting to X last week, Prince asked if anyone wanted any general feedback, declaring that he felt &#8220;in an especially truthful mood.&#8221; The first <a href="https://x.com/cisne_bayswater/status/1924962395010584847">response</a> contained direct questions about the LaLiga controversy, the blame for which LaLiga places squarely on the shoulders of Cloudflare. </p>
<p>For the first time since Cloudflare legal action <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/judge-confirms-laligas-right-to-block-cloudflare-in-pursuit-of-iptv-pirates-250328/">failed to end LaLiga&#8217;s blocking campaign</a>, Prince weighed in with his assessment of the current situation and where he believes it&#8217;s inevitably heading.</p>
<h2>&#8220;Bonkers&#8221; Blocking Strategy</h2>
<p>&#8220;A huge percentage of the Internet sits behind us, including small businesses and emergency resources in Spain,&#8221; Prince explained. </p>
<p>&#8220;The strategy of blocking broadly through ISPs based on IPs is bonkers because so much content, including emergency services content, can be behind any IP. <a href="https://x.com/eastdakota/status/1924969551478804543">The collateral damage is vast</a> and is hurting Spanish citizens from accessing critical resources,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, various comments and statements by LaLiga suggested that its relationship with Cloudflare had reached rock bottom. It transpired that LaLiga had <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/cloudflare-asks-court-to-end-laligas-illegal-blocking-response-to-encrypted-client-hello-250220/">obtained an injunction</a> which allowed it to tackle Cloudflare and <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/announcing-encrypted-client-hello/">Encrypted Client Hello (ECH)</a>, but had done so without Cloudflare&#8217;s knowledge, effectively denying the company a right to respond.</p>
<p>Alongside other attacks delivered via the media, LaLiga slammed Cloudflare for refusing to cooperate. What action LaLiga had demanded still isn&#8217;t clear, but the league said that if there was any overblocking as a result, Cloudflare would have to shoulder the blame.</p>
<h2>The Potential for Deadly Consequences</h2>
<p>The scale of overblocking reported in Spain is unprecedented but since LaLiga has a court order that effectively gives Cloudflare blocking a green light, it has been doing so in bulk, every single week since February.</p>
<p>Depending on who addresses the overblocking issue, with whom and when, the league claims that collateral damage a) doesn&#8217;t exist or is minimal and/or b) is Cloudflare&#8217;s responsibility. Prince appears to have grave concerns over the scale and type of blocking taking place, warning that a worst-case scenario is inevitable.</p>
<h2>Football Piracy Blocks Will Claim Lives</h2>
<p>Despite LaLiga&#8217;s unshakable claims to the contrary, Prince believes that it&#8217;s not a case of &#8216;if&#8217; disaster strikes, it&#8217;s &#8216;when&#8217;.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s only a matter of time before a Spanish citizen can&#8217;t access a life-saving emergency resource because the rights holder in a football match refuses to send a limited request to block one resource versus a broad request to block a whole swath of the Internet,&#8221; Prince warned.</p>
<p>&#8220;When that unfortunately and inevitably happens and harms lives, I&#8217;m confident policy makers and courts in Spain and elsewhere will make the right policy decision. Until then, it&#8217;ll be up to users to make politicians clear on the risk. I pray no one dies.&#8221;</p>
<p>The suggestion that LaLiga&#8217;s demands were too broad, doesn&#8217;t mean that Cloudflare is refusing to help, Prince suggested. On the contrary, there&#8217;s a process available, LaLiga just needs to use it.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve always been happy and willing to work with rights holders in conjunction with judicial bodies to protect their content. We have a clear process that works around the world to do that, Prince explained.</p>
<h2>LaLiga Targeted Cloudflare and Others During the Weekend</h2>
<p>Live blocking data provided by <a href="https://hayahora.futbol/">hayahora.futbol</a> has proven invaluable to those documenting #laligagate in recent months and this past weekend was no different. </p>
<p>As the small sample of Cloudflare IP addresses blocked on Sunday seems to show, concerns that every IP address blocked would inevitably result in collateral damage, seem to have been trumped by the authority of the now-famous court order.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-top-blocked.png" alt="laliga-top-blocked" width="670" height="1146" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267856" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-top-blocked.png 975w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-top-blocked-300x513.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-top-blocked-600x1026.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-top-blocked-88x150.png 88w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-top-blocked-898x1536.png 898w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>The importance of strict adherence to the law was underlined by LaLiga&#8217;s Global Content Protection Manager in a recent interview.</p>
<p>José Ignacio Carrillo de Albornoz told <a href="https://www.elconfidencial.com/deportes/2025-05-19/pirateria-iptv-ilegal-futbol-carrillo-albornoz-laliga-bra_4130314/">El Confidencial</a> that without the collaboration of intermediaries, piracy will be impossible to beat. Carrillo de Albornoz concluded with a &#8220;statement of responsibility&#8221; which notes that real progress will require all parties to work together and go beyond compliance with the law.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is necessary that all links in the digital chain act legally and ethically,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-recordv.png" alt="laliga-recordv" width="550" height="502" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267867" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-recordv.png 726w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-recordv-300x274.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-recordv-600x548.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/laliga-recordv-150x137.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></center></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>P.CoK Webtoon Piracy Fighters Display Plumage as Unorthodox Tactics Pay Off</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/p-cok-webtoon-piracy-fighters-display-plumage-as-unorthodox-tactics-pay-off-250525/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 07:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kakao entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p.cok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The anti-piracy team at Kakao Entertainment likes to stand out and not just when there's good news to report. Like the avian beauty that inspired its name, P.CoK's approach is part eye-catching, part distraction, but it does appear to be working. With help from what it describes as an underground network of volunteer informants, P.CoK claims to have shut down 28 pirate sites. It also posts 'insider' evidence and items of proof to social media, to dispel any lingering doubt.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/p-cok-logo-s1-e1747876256856.png" alt="p-cok-logo-s1" width="250" height="250" class="alignright size-full wp-image-267693" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/p-cok-logo-s1-e1747876256856.png 498w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/p-cok-logo-s1-e1747876256856-300x301.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/p-cok-logo-s1-e1747876256856-150x150.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 250px) 100vw, 250px" />If it was possible to strip away the roles and behaviors that inevitably lead to head-on clashes, in some cases pirates and piracy fighters might find ways to get along. In some cases they may love the same things.</p>
<p>Yet back in the real world, the insatiable appetite for pirated content owned or protected by the latter, means the war never ends, only the shape changes. Whether South Korean publishing company Kakao Entertainment had always intended to do something different isn&#8217;t clear, but when it comes to presentation, no equivalent approach to fighting piracy exists at scale anywhere else.</p>
<h2>The Krew</h2>
<p>Launched in 2021 to proactively protect Kakao Entertainment’s &#8216;webtoon&#8217; comic library, the new &#8216;P.CoK&#8217; anti-piracy unit&#8217;s name was inspired by the &#8216;eyes&#8217; on a peacock&#8217;s feathers. </p>
<p>&#8220;We’re always on the lookout for illegal use of Kakao Entertainment’s exclusive content worldwide,&#8221; the Kakao &#8216;Krew&#8217; explained in 2023. </p>
<p>P.CoK conceded that it couldn&#8217;t yet put a figure on the scale of the piracy it was addressing or the monetary value of any losses attributable to it. Of course, even the wider industry has to settle for best estimates, so a fairly blunt but honest admission was fundamentally credible, yet also quite rare.</p>
<p>At the time, forming a complete database of pirate sites responsible for sharing Kakao content remained a work in progress. On the prevention side, P.CoK reported working with watermarking, image recognition, and usage pattern analysis, which helped the team &#8220;keep an eye on things and nip illegal activity in the bud.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Complete the Quest, Level Up</h2>
<p>Like much of the corporate world, anti-piracy work and how it&#8217;s presented to the outside world may at times undergo a little cosmetic filtering, to send the right message or benefit from being seen in a particular light. </p>
<p>Due to the nature of the work there may be an element of misdirection, especially when the target audience are those the company and often the police are determined to catch.</p>
<p>In P.CoK&#8217;s case, some things that are so neat and perfect, you really, <em>really</em> want them to be true. Maybe they are.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/qaaMC53IMH.png" alt="p.cok" width="200" height="65" class="alignright size-full wp-image-267816" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/qaaMC53IMH.png 517w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/qaaMC53IMH-300x97.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/qaaMC53IMH-150x49.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<h2>Piracy Culture, Videogame Culture? No Problem</h2>
<p>As presented, there are three people in the team, all quite young with great names &#8211; Xeno, Hani, and Jeno. These people undoubtedly understand Kakao&#8217;s audience, especially those who prefer not to pay.</p>
<p>P.CoK also enjoys webtoons and without getting too personal, one spent a number of years as a webtoon producer. Then the icing on the cake &#8211; at least two are gamers. One likens shutting down a site to &#8220;clearing a stage&#8221; in a game and the other focuses on anti-piracy strategic planning and then &#8220;leveling up after completing a quest.&#8221;</p>
<p><small><em>Update: An earlier version of this article described a team member as a &#8216;webtoon artist&#8217;. P.CoK informs us they actually worked for several years as a webtoon producer. &#8220;He was notably involved in producing globally recognized titles such as Itaewon Class and Burning Effect,&#8221; P.CoK clarifies.</em></small></p>
<h2>Documenting Progress</h2>
<p>The publication of an anti-piracy white paper every six months (Sixth Edition <a href="https://newsroom.kakaoent.com/news/6th-anti-piracy-whitepaper-kakao-entertainment-launches-1st-ever-comprehensive-crackdown-system-for-webtoons-and-web-novels-blocks-240-million-illegal-cases/">here</a>) provides an overview of progress and challenges in Kakao&#8217;s fight against piracy.</p>
<p>As reported in February&#8217;s edition, <em>a total of 240 million illegal content removals worldwide in the second half of 2024</em> contributed to a <em>grand total of 740 million removals overall</em>. This was made possible by Kakao&#8217;s Trusted Copyright Removal Program (TCRP) status at Google, and the small matter of <em>filing 30,000 takedown requests every day</em>. </p>
<p>Some rightsholders use their takedown notice volumes as a proxy for progress in the fight against piracy; at least in the beginning, the removal of a million links to pirated content tends to speak for itself. Yet when Kakao mentions a 10.9% decrease in takedown notices in its sixth White Paper, compared to the number cited in the fifth, the reduction represents progress instead.</p>
<p>The decline was largely attributed to P.CoK&#8217;s long-term monitoring and the subsequent shutdown of a &#8220;major domestic&#8221; pirate site. Kakao identifies the platform as site &#8220;A&#8221;, almost certainly a reference to Agitoon and the linked Agitoon Novel sites shut down in a law enforcement operation last August.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/kakaopage.png" alt="kakaopage" width="670" height="150" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267779" /></center></p>
<p>&#8220;The case underscores the critical role of site shutdowns in reducing overall piracy activity,&#8221; Kakao noted in February. &#8220;Kakao Entertainment has consistently emphasized that shutting down a site by identifying its operator is at the core of its response to illegal distribution.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rare outlier examples aside, when a site operator&#8217;s anonymity is compromised, that can forever change the game. Anti-piracy outfits tend to keep unmasking details secret for operational reasons. P.CoK likes to tell those stories on social media.</p>
<h2>Raising Awareness, Recruiting Informants</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/p-cok-9a.png" alt="p-cok-9a" width="260" height="204" class="alignright size-full wp-image-267736" />The theory that raising awareness of piracy discourages illegal consumption, is being tested in several ongoing campaigns. Spreading the message that piracy hurts everyone involved in creating webtoons, is one of P.CoK&#8217;s responsibilities. </p>
<p>The day-to-day platform of choice for raising awareness is Twitter. At what point spreading the gospel of Kindness to Creators began its transformation isn&#8217;t clear, but today the <a href="https://x.com/kakaoent_pcok">P.CoK account on X</a> is much more than that. </p>
<p>Acting as a notice board for P.CoK&#8217;s anti-piracy activities and the availability of legal content, the channel also encourages webtoon fans to report links to illegal content, wherever they exist online. </p>
<p>For fans and supporters prepared to go further, P.CoK&#8217;s channel on X acts as a recruitment office for informants. After obtaining useful information from piracy circles, they head back to base where the information is relayed to P.CoK for enforcement purposes. </p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/spy-recruit.png" alt="spy-recruit" width="540" height="346" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267724" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/spy-recruit.png 787w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/spy-recruit-300x192.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/spy-recruit-600x384.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/spy-recruit-150x96.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></center></p>
<p>Having gathered a number of willing informants over the last couple of years, P.CoK claims to have built an underground network that actively supports its <em>One Point Response System</em>.</p>
<h2>Shutting Sites Down Using Any Legal Means</h2>
<p>Traditional wisdom suggests that revealing details of an anti-piracy enforcement plan up front may introduce unnecessary risk. Yet having shared the details of its <em>One Point Response System</em> with TorrentFreak recently, at face value P.CoK probably thinks otherwise.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/one-point-response.png" alt="one-point-response" width="670" height="136" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267743" /></center></p>
<p>P.CoK&#8217;s response to infringement begins with TTT: <strong>T</strong>argeting, <strong>T</strong>racing, and <strong>T</strong>akedown. It&#8217;s at this early stage that the technical aspects, operations, revenue streams, and<br />
community details of pirate sites are gathered together, and cross-referenced with P.CoK&#8217;s databases of illegal site operators and the networks they operate in.</p>
<p>After combining and analyzing all available information, a shortlist of suspected site operators is compared with a list of actual operators. After final verification, the next stage can begin.</p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/process-pcok.png" alt="process-pcok" width="670" height="199" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267745" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/process-pcok.png 670w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/process-pcok-300x89.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/process-pcok-600x178.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/process-pcok-150x45.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>P.CoK says that it reaches out to the operators of pirate sites and services via &#8220;legally effective communications&#8221; such as email or physical documents. From the information available to us, the strategy seems to rely on operators believing there&#8217;s a credible threat of escalation, but they hold none of the cards.</p>
<h2>Anonymity Gone &#8211; Choose a Poison</h2>
<p>With the clear emphasis being placed on removing all anonymity, proving that to be the case will likely support efforts to convince operators that anything other than total capitulation is already a lost cause. Those who push back could face civil or criminal action. </p>
<p>Those who decide to comply and throw in the towel are expected to post a public announcement, shut down their site, and pledge never to infringe again. These final &#8216;goodbye&#8217; statements are also posted on X, where the consequences of non-compliance are on display, presumably for the benefit of others in a similar position. It&#8217;s the modern-day equivalent of a severed head on a pike, with a comfortable chair and maybe a beer as a tempting potential off-ramp.</p>
<p><center><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/light-novel-pub.png.webp"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/light-novel-pub.png" alt="light novel pub" width="670" height="151" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267746" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/light-novel-pub.png 1489w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/light-novel-pub-300x68.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/light-novel-pub-600x135.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/light-novel-pub-150x34.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></a></center></p>
<p>Of course, there are no restrictions on who can read these types of notices, which range from members of the public curious about content being made available for free, to lower tier pirate site staff and uploaders nervous about maintaining anonymity. </p>
<p>Even those daydreaming about launching a site of their own one day might stumble upon one of the statements below and take a different course.</p>
<p><center><em>So Long, and Thanks for All the Fish</em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/shutdowns-p-cok.png" alt="shutdowns-p-cok" width="670" height="400" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267775" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/shutdowns-p-cok.png 1223w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/shutdowns-p-cok-300x179.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/shutdowns-p-cok-600x359.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/shutdowns-p-cok-150x90.png 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/shutdowns-p-cok-220x130.png 220w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>Anti-piracy outfits aren&#8217;t typically known for seeking this type of attention. That being said, we assume P.CoK only has to take Kakao&#8217;s interests into account and having agreed the parameters, it simply gets on with the job. We&#8217;re informed that the total number of sites shut down has risen to 28 following the sudden closure of Reaper Scans <a href="https://x.com/kakaoent_pcok/status/1922564468153975162">announced this week</a>.</p>
<p>A &#8216;goodbye&#8217; message posted by the operators of Reaper Scans revealed that the demise of the 10 million visits per month site was triggered by a cease-and-desist notice received via email. It transpires that P.CoK had identified three Reaper Scans operators in as many countries (United States, India and Croatia) and for good measure, addressed them personally using their real names.</p>
<h2>Why Reveal the Plan and Who Benefits?</h2>
<p>While the plan is quite detailed, specific, and at times, fairly elaborate, it contains no information useful to pirate site operators. Equally, there&#8217;s no sign of anything that undermines P.CoK or Kakao or the strategy itself. That naturally leads to the obvious question: who benefits from the details being made public?</p>
<p>Assuming that this is a true representation of P.CoK&#8217;s plan, it&#8217;s fundamentally solid; identify the suspects, leave no space for maneuver, provide an exit strategy, and work hard in advance to ensure that despite the presence of choice, site operators have only one viable option.</p>
<p>Indeed, by being unambiguous about how things are likely to play out, at all times there&#8217;s a tacit understanding over where this will inevitably end up for the freshly deanonymized. The joker in the pack concerns the informants; how many actually exist, or do any exist at all? Are they effective? Who are they?</p>
<p>To the extent that answers to any of those questions are in any way helpful, pirate site communities have been known to self corrode from excessive suspicion alone. </p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/global-informants.png" alt="global-informants" width="670" height="288" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267782" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/global-informants.png 719w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/global-informants-300x129.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/global-informants-600x258.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/global-informants-150x64.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Piracy Shield: European Commission Urged to Assess Legality Under EU Law</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/piracy-shield-tech-giants-urge-commission-to-assess-legality-under-eu-law-250524/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 08:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Site Blocking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ccia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Expressing grave concerns over Italy's  Piracy Shield system, this January tech and telecoms advocacy group CCIA urged the government to withdraw planned legislation and engage TRIS, an EU procedure which aims to prevent internal market barriers. In a newly submitted contribution under TRIS, CCIA urges the European Commission to issue a detailed opinion to ensure Piracy Shield's compatibility with EU law.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pshield-fix1-s.png" alt="pshield-fix1-s" width="300" height="181" class="alignright size-full wp-image-266076" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/pshield-fix1-s.png 450w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pshield-fix1-s-300x181.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/pshield-fix1-s-150x90.png 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Praised by major rightsholders as progress in the fight against piracy, Italy&#8217;s Piracy Shield system made headlines for all the wrong reasons.</p>
<p>Authorized under new legislation and promoted as a killer blow to piracy of live sports, Piracy Shield&#8217;s launch soon descended into a series of overblocking blunders and international news headlines. Realization that Piracy Shield was incapable of living up to the hype, led to <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/italy-approves-piracy-shield-vpn-dns-proposal-risk-of-prison-for-isps-intact-241001/">legal amendments</a> that contained direct threats against the tech sector.</p>
<h2>CCIA Intervenes On Behalf of the Tech Sector</h2>
<p>The Computer &#038; Communications Industry Association (CCIA) represents global tech giants including Amazon, Apple, Cloudflare, Google, and Meta, among others. In a January 2025 letter to the EU Commission, CCIA acknowledged that Piracy Shield exists to protect rightsholders but warned that the blocking mechanism is a &#8220;<a href="https://torrentfreak.com/tech-industry-urges-eu-to-halt-italys-overreaching-anti-piracy-measures-250122/">blunt instrument</a>&#8221; that threatens businesses and the public alike.</p>
<p>When telecoms regulator AGCOM launched a public consultation on proposed amendments to copyright regulations and Piracy Shield&#8217;s operations, CCIA took the opportunity to restate its concerns. Highlighting the risk of overblocking, CCIA turned to the blocking requests made by rightsholders and a requirement under Italian law to execute them within 30 minutes.</p>
<p>&#8220;[W]e believe that the Piracy Shield poses significant risks to the principles of freedom of enterprise expression, as established by European and Italian law,” CCIA <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/tech-giants-propose-critical-piracy-shield-regulation-amendments-250409/">wrote</a>.</p>
<h2>CCIA Urges European Commission to Intervene</h2>
<p>After months of engagement, including its letter to the European Commission back in January, CCIA&#8217;s latest submission calls on the Commission to seize the opportunity to publish a detailed opinion to address Piracy Shield&#8217;s apparent incompatibility with EU law. </p>
<p>CCIA&#8217;s submission to AGCOM begins by highlighting the proposed amendments.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Piracy Shield allows copyright holders to request site-blocking orders to be executed within 30 minutes, with limited transparency or recourse for affected parties. </p>
<p>&#8220;These amendments, most notably changes to Article 10 and Article 8 (3-bis) of the Regulation, further consolidate the Shield&#8217;s role, including extraterritorial content-removal capabilities without clear coordination with EU law, particularly the Digital Services Act (DSA),&#8221; CCIA&#8217;s submission reads.</p>
<p>&#8220;Given the serious implications of these proposals for the EU internal market, the freedom to provide cross-border services, and fundamental rights such as freedom of expression and due process, CCIA Europe urges the Commission to issue a detailed opinion under the TRIS procedure.&#8221;</p>
<h2>TRIS &#8211; Prevention of Technical Barriers to Trade</h2>
<p>One of the basic principles of the European Union is an internal market that embraces the free movement of people, goods, services, and capital. Mechanisms that restrict or have the effect of restricting such movement, may create prohibited &#8216;internal frontiers&#8217;.</p>
<p>The aim of the TRIS procedure (<a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dir/2015/1535/oj/eng">Directive 2015/1535</a>) is to identify and prevent the appearance of internal barriers before they can have a negative effect on the market. Under TRIS, notifications sent to the European Commission may lead to a legal analysis in light of EU law.</p>
<p>CCIA&#8217;s submission draws attention to key issues that it believes should be assessed by the Commission, summarized as follows:</p>
<p><strong>Lack of procedural safeguards and transparency in the Piracy Shield platform</strong></p>
<p>• <em>Blocking requests processed automatically, does not seem AGCOM checks for accuracy.</em><br />
• <em>No meaningful opportunity to contest blocking orders before enforcement.</em><br />
• <em>No independent review or appeal mechanism that operates in a timely manner.</em><br />
• <em>Piracy Shield technical specs and operational protocols have never been made public.</em><br />
• <em>Development and governance lacked stakeholder inclusivity.</em><br />
• <em>Platform incompatible with principles of proportionality and due process</em></p>
<p><strong>Risk of overblocking and collateral damage</strong> covers known incidents of overblocking, including the event that caused a widespread outage of Google Drive and the blocking of shared IP addresses at Cloudflare. </p>
<p>In general, blocking of shared IP addresses &#8220;poses a high risk of unjustified interference with lawful online content and services&#8221; while domain name blocking &#8220;heightens the potential for overreach and content censorship, particularly when a single domain may host a mix [of] infringing and non-infringing content.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Questionable legal basis for cross-border removal</strong></p>
<p><em>AGCOM&#8217;s new proposal introduces a provision empowering itself to issue orders for the removal of content hosted in other EU Member States, vaguely referring to the Digital Services Act (DSA) as a legal basis. This raises several concerns:</em></p>
<p>• <em>The DSA provides for structured cross-border cooperation mechanisms and does not grant national authorities carte blanche to take direct enforcement action against hosting services in other Member States.</em></p>
<p>• <em>The proposal lacks clarity on which provisions of the DSA are being invoked and how these powers align with Articles 8 and 9 of the DSA, which govern the issuance and enforcement of orders to act against illegal content.</em></p>
<p>• <em>This extraterritorial enforcement risks undermining the DSA&#8217;s country-of-origin principle and creates legal uncertainty for service providers operating across the EU.</em></p>
<p>The final section in the submission titled <strong>Ineffectiveness of network-level blocking</strong> notes that blocking is easily circumvented and does not remove any infringing content from the internet. Blocking can also &#8220;serve to obscure&#8221; rather than address the root causes of piracy. Overall, better options exist. </p>
<p>That leads CCIA to its conclusions and a brief summary of its key points and concerns. </p>
<p><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/ec-piracy-test.png" alt="ec-piracy-test" width="670" height="393" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-267833" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/ec-piracy-test.png 884w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/ec-piracy-test-300x176.png 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/ec-piracy-test-600x352.png 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/ec-piracy-test-150x88.png 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/ec-piracy-test-220x130.png 220w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></center></p>
<p>No timeline is mentioned in respect of a decision for or against an assessment, or how long a subsequent opinion could take to arrive.</p>
<p><em>The full CCIA submission is available <a href="https://ccianet.org/library/tris-italys-piracy-shield-ccia-europes-contribution/">here</a> (pdf)</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU Piracy Watchlist Adds IPFS, FitGirl and Njalla</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/eu-piracy-watchlist-adds-ipfs-fitgirl-and-njalla-250523/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Law and Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piracy watch list]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The European Commission has published the fourth edition of its 'Counterfeit and Piracy Watch List', providing a detailed overview of piracy-linked sites and services located outside the EU. Aside from many familiar names such as The Pirate Bay, the report also flags the InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) as a piracy threat. Game repacker FitGirl and domain registration service Njalla also make the list, with the latter surprisingly branded as an 'off-the-shelf piracy facilitation service'</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/ipfs-lo.jpg" alt="ipfs logo" width="300" height="161" class="alignright size-full wp-image-241227" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/ipfs-lo.jpg 444w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/ipfs-lo-300x161.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Over the past two decades, online piracy has proven to be a massive headache for the entertainment industries.</p>
<p>Governments around the world have recognized this challenge and, where possible, lend a helping hand to identify and address the threats.</p>
<p>The European Commission, for example, compiles a biennial ‘Counterfeit and Piracy Watch List’, following the example set by the United States. Like its U.S. equivalent, the EU watchlist relies on <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/eu-invites-feedback-from-pirate-sites-for-upcoming-watchlist-240623/">input from copyright holders</a>, which nominate problematic sites and services for inclusion.</p>
<h2>New Threats</h2>
<p>This week the Commission released its latest version of the Counterfeit and Piracy Watch List. The report provides a detailed overview of the piracy landscape including statistics from many studies that were previously published. In addition, it highlights what are seen as the most serious threats today.</p>
<p>Compared to the previous edition, there appears to be a stronger focus on game piracy. Several new additions are gaming-related, including the elusive repacker <em>FitGirl</em> and several <em>NSW2U</em> domain names. Both have been blocked by ISPs in several EU countries. </p>
<p><center><em>FitGirl</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/firgirlrepack.jpg" alt="fitgirl" width="600" height="154" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267798" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/firgirlrepack.jpg 962w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/firgirlrepack-300x77.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/firgirlrepack-600x154.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/firgirlrepack-150x39.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<p>Other newcomers are the streaming repository <em>Doodstream</em>, sports streaming site <em>Pirlo TV</em>, hosting provider <em>Virtual Systems</em>, IPTV service <em>GenIPTV</em> and the pirate video library <em>Vidsrc</em>.</p>
<h2>Njalla: Off-the-Shelf Piracy Service?</h2>
<p>Another new target is <a href="https://njal.la/">Njalla</a>, the privacy-focused domain registration intermediary <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-bay-founder-launches-anonymous-domain-registration-service-170419/">founded</a> by Pirate Bay co-founder Peter Sunde. The service is operated by Saint Kitts and Nevis-based 1337 Services.</p>
<p>According to the EU report, Njalla appears to do more than simply registering domains for its customers. Allegedly, it allows people to launch a complete pirate site using the service. </p>
<p>&#8220;This off-the-shelf piracy facilitation service makes it easy for would-be pirates to create and monetise a fully functioning pirate service,&#8221; the EU report reads. </p>
<p><center><em>From EU&#8217;s Watch List</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/njallaerror.jpg" alt="njalla description" width="967" height="340" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267770" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/njallaerror.jpg 967w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/njallaerror-300x105.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/njallaerror-600x211.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/njallaerror-150x53.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 967px) 100vw, 967px" /></center></p>
<p>This description does not fit Njalla as we know it. However, it can be explained. Apparently, the the EU Commission appears to apply the general description of &#8220;Piracy as a Service&#8221; (PaaS) providers to Njalla. While MPA previously reported Njalla as a PaaS service (to the USTR), applying the full description seems out of place here.</p>
<p><center><em>From MPA&#8217;s 2024 recommendation to the USTR</em></center><br /><center><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/paas.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="251" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267771" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/paas.jpg 1113w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/paas-300x125.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/paas-600x251.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/paas-150x63.jpg 150w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/paas-500x210.jpg 500w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></center></p>
<p>In its submission, MPA argued that PaaS services, taken together, make it easy for aspiring pirates to launch their own services. However, Njalla itself does not allow &#8220;pirates to create and monetise a fully functioning pirate service&#8221; as the EU Commission suggests. That&#8217;s a concerning error, to say the least.</p>
<p>The PaaS term was originally coined years ago. We first noticed it in a <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/hollywood-and-netflix-signal-piracy-as-a-service-paas-as-new-threat-vector/">MPA report in 2021</a>, where the same &#8220;off the shelf&#8221; terminology was used.</p>
<h2>IPFS</h2>
<p>The final newcomer to stand out is the InterPlanetary File System, more broadly known as <a href="https://ipfs.tech/">IPFS</a>. This is a decentralized network where users make files available to each other. The system makes websites censorship resistant and not vulnerable to regular hosting outages.</p>
<p>These advantages allow archivists, content creators, researchers, and many others to reliably distribute large volumes of data over the Internet. Wikipedia has used it&#8217;s for example, and Lockheed Martin helped to launch an IPFS node into space.</p>
<p>However, the same censorship-resistant features also <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/pirate-sites-exploit-interplanetary-file-system-gateways-publishers-warn-231013/">appeal to pirate sites</a>, which is why the EU has now included it on its watch list. The same applies to the Interplanetary Distributed Literature Catalog (IPDL), which maintains links to torrent and IPFS archives.</p>
<p>&#8220;Super Pirate and the major pirate networks, including Library Genesis (LibGen), Z-Library, Anna’s Archive are reported to use public gateways to host and distribute copyrighted materials on IPFS,&#8221; the report reads.</p>
<h2>Usual Suspects</h2>
<p>In addition to roughly a dozen fresh entries, the EU watchlist includes many familiar websites. Torrent sites such as The Pirate Bay, 1337x, and Rutracker make an appearance, similar to previous years. </p>
<p>Fmovies is still mentioned too, despite <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/fmovies-piracy-ring-was-shut-down-by-vietnam-assisted-by-ace-240829/">its shutdown</a> last year. Instead of the original site, the EU Watch list now includes two copycat Fmovies sites; fmoviesto.site and f-moviesz.to. </p>
<p>The music category, meanwhile, is dominated by stream-ripping services, while publishing companies highlighted Sci-Hub and LibGen as persistent threats. The full list is completed by various hosting companies, IPTV services, and pirate apps and tools.</p>
<p>While all currently listed sites and services would likely prefer to remain unmentioned, there are no immediate consequences, at least as far as the EU is concerned. </p>
<p>The EU Commission notes that the Piracy Watch List mainly serves to encourage operators and owners, as well as local governments and enforcement authorities, to take appropriate action to reduce online piracy.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> After publication, ISTQ management informed us that it was surprised to be included in the report, while clarifying its position.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;ISTQ does not support, promote, or knowingly host any illegal services, including unlicensed IPTV. On the contrary, we have permanently suspended many client accounts in the past after receiving verified abuse reports related to such activities.</p>
<p>As a hosting provider, we receive new clients daily, and while we are unable to pre-screen the nature of their businesses, we take immediate action when any activity in violation of our terms or applicable laws is identified.</p>
<p>We operate under clear abuse handling procedures and cooperate fully with copyright holders and legal authorities. Our logs and actions are well documented and available for review upon request.</p>
<p>We are open to constructive dialogue and welcome any feedback on how we can strengthen our policies even further. We believe it’s important that infrastructure providers who act in good faith are treated fairly.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>—-</p>
<p>A copy of the European Commission’s fourth Counterfeit and Piracy Watch List is available <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/SWD2025132_0.pdf">here (pdf)</a>. A list of all the online piracy targets and intermediaries can be found below.</em></p>
<p>Cyberlockers</p>
<p>– Mega.nz/.io<br />
<strike>– Uptobox.com / Uptostream.com</strike><br />
– Rapidgator.net<br />
<strike>– Uploaded.net (ul.to, uploaded.to)</strike><br />
– Dbree.org<br />
<em>&#8211; Doodstream (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Z-Library (new)</em></p>
<p>Stream-Rippers</p>
<p><em>&#8211; YTMP3.CC, Ytmp3.nu (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; X2mate.com (new)</em><br />
– Y2mate.com and related sites<br />
– Savefrom.net /ssyoutube.com/sfrom.ne<br />
<strike>– Flvto.biz and 2conv.com</strike><br />
<strike>– Snappea.com</strike></p>
<p>Linking or referring websites</p>
<p>– Fmovies (clones, fmoviesto.site, f-moviesz.to)<br />
– Seasonvar.ru<br />
– Rlsbb.ru<br />
– Rezka.ag<br />
<em>&#8211; Dytt8[.]net, Dytt89.com, Dy2018.net, Dy2018[.]com, Dydytt[.]net, and Ygdy8[.]com (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Hianime (formerly Aniwatch[.]to and zoro[.]to) (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Cuevana[.]biz and Cuevana3[.]eu, Cuevana3[.]ch, Cuevana.is (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; nsw2u.xyz/nsw2u.com/nsw2u.net (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; fitgirl-repacks.site (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Pirlo TV (new)</em></p>
<p>Peer-to-peer and BitTorrent indexing websites</p>
<p>– ThePirateBay.org (and related domains)<br />
<strike>– Rarbg.to</strike><br />
– Rutracker.org<br />
– 1337x.to<br />
<em>&#8211; Interplanetary Distributed Literature Catalog (IPDL) (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) (new)</em></p>
<p>Unlicensed download sites</p>
<p><strike>– Music-Bazaar.com and Music-Bazaar.mobi</strike><br />
– Sci-hub.io (Sci-hub.tw; sci-hub.cc; sci-hub.ac; sci-hub.bz and others)<br />
– Libgen.onl and mirror sites</p>
<p>Piracy Apps</p>
<p>– IPTV Smarters<br />
– Ievpad.com<br />
&#8211; MagisTV<br />
<strike>– Shabakaty</strike></p>
<p>Hosting providers</p>
<p>– DDoS-Guard.net<br />
– Private Layer<br />
<em>&#8211; Virtual Systems, V-Sys (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Squitter, ABC Consultancy, Peenq, ESTOXY, BestDC, SERDECHS (new)</em><br />
– “Amarutu”, also known as Koddos<br />
– AS-Istqservers / Istqserverses (“Istq”)<br />
– HostPalace Web Solution PVT LTD (“Host Palace”)</p>
<p>Unlicensed IPTV services</p>
<p><strike>– BIPTV.best and BestBuyIPTV.store</strike><br />
– King365tv.com / Theking365tv.pro, Theking365tv.site<br />
– VolkaIPTV.com /.ru<br />
<em>&#8211; GenIPTV (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Dark IPTV (new)</em></p>
<p>Piracy Supporting Services</p>
<p>– 2embed.ru; 2embed, or 2embed[.]cc / 2embed[.]skin<br />
<strike>– Fembed.com</strike><br />
<em>&#8211; Vidsrc[.]to (new)</em><br />
<em>&#8211; Njal[.]la – 1337 Services (new) </em><br />
<em>&#8211; GDrivePlayer (new)</em></p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>YouTube Processed 2.2 Billion Content ID Copyright Claims in 2024</title>
		<link>https://torrentfreak.com/youtube-processed-2-2-billion-content-id-copyright-claims-in-2024-250522/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ernesto Van der Sar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 10:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DMCA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content ID]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transparency Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://torrentfreak.com/?p=267513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>YouTube's Content ID system processed a record-breaking 2.2 billion copyright claims in 2024, with automated detection accounting for more than 99% of the total. According to YouTube, rightsholders chose to monetize the content in the overwhelming majority of claims. Revenue paid out to content creators and owners through the Content ID system now exceeds $12 billion since inception.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/content-id-1.jpg" alt="content-id" width="300" height="200" class="alignright size-full wp-image-217048" />To protect copyright holders, YouTube regularly removes, disables, or demonetizes videos that contain allegedly infringing content.</p>
<p>For years, little was known about the scope of these copyright claims. That changed three years ago when the streaming platform published its <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/youtube-processes-4-million-content-id-claims-per-day-transparency-report-reveals-211207/">first-ever transparency report</a>.</p>
<p>The report showed that roughly 99% of all copyright claims on YouTube are handled through the Content ID system. Since many claims are automated, without human intervention, access is restricted to a few thousand vetted rightsholders.</p>
<h2>4,564 Users, 2.2 Billion Claims</h2>
<p>Published this week, YouTube&#8217;s latest <a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com/youtube-copyright/intro">Transparency Report</a> shows that the number of automated claims continues to rise. In 2024, the streaming platform processed over 2.2 billion claims, up from nearly 2 billion a year earlier. </p>
<p>YouTube reports that of the 7,703 rightsholders who currently have access to the system, 4,564 actively use it. That&#8217;s a relatively small number when compared to the 308,556 users who filed just over 3 million claims through the online takedown form.</p>
<p><center><em>YouTube&#8217;s 2024 copyright claims</em></center><br /><center><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/youid.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://torrentfreak.com/images/youid.jpg" alt="youtube copyright id 2024" width="600" height="478" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267658" srcset="https://torrentfreak.com/images/youid.jpg 1311w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/youid-300x239.jpg 300w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/youid-600x478.jpg 600w, https://torrentfreak.com/images/youid-150x120.jpg 150w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></center></p>
<p>The report reveals that 99.43% of all copyright actions taken on the platform throughout the year are processed by the Content ID system. These are mostly automated claims, but Content ID users also flagged content manually in 0.31% of cases. </p>
<p>This tiny percentage might not sound like much but, at this scale, it translates to approximately 6.9 million manual claims. </p>
<h2>Disputed Claims</h2>
<p>Despite the immense volume of claims, the number of disputed claims remains relatively low. Fewer than 1% of the over 2.2 billion Content ID claims were disputed by recipients in 2024. That’s <em>relatively</em> low, although one percent still equates to 22 million disputes.</p>
<p>Interestingly, manually generated claims were more than twice as likely to be disputed (1.13%) compared to those made via automated detection (0.54%). This suggests that human intervention triggers more complaints. </p>
<p>Challenges against Copyright claims are often filed for good reason. According to the report, over 65% of Content ID claim disputes in 2024 were resolved in favor of the uploader. This typically happens because claimants voluntarily released their claim or did not respond in time.</p>
<h2>A &#8220;$12 Billion&#8221; Money Machine</h2>
<p>While Content ID can be a major source of frustration for YouTubers, it has become a goldmine for rightsholders. Instead of removing infringing videos, most rightsholders prefer to monetize them through YouTube instead. </p>
<p>Rightsholders chose to monetize over 90% of all Content ID claims in 2024. As a result, the advertising revenue from these videos is shared with the claiming parties instead of the uploaders. </p>
<p>This monetization strategy has proven to generate substantial revenues for claimants. Since inception, YouTube has paid out $12 billion in revenue for copyright claims originating from the Content ID system.</p>
<h2>Access Restricted</h2>
<p>The numbers reported above only apply to the Content ID system. While it&#8217;s responsible for nearly all copyright actions on YouTube, those who are not part of the system must use other options, such as the webform or the <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/youtube-launches-copyright-match-tool-protect-initial-uploaders-180712/">Copyright Match Tool</a>. </p>
<p>Many other rightsholders would like access to Content ID, but YouTube intentionally limits participation to a few thousand vetted users.  </p>
<p>One of the reasons YouTube limits use of Content ID to a relatively small group, is the potential for damage. An inaccurate or abusive reference file can result in thousands of false claims.</p>
<p>&#8220;In Content ID the impact is multiplied due to its automated nature; one bad reference file can impact hundreds or even thousands of videos across the site,&#8221; YouTube writes. </p>
<p>&#8220;In one highly publicized instance, a news channel uploaded public domain footage from NASA of a Mars rover and ended up making inappropriate claims against all other news channels and creators using the same footage, even against the NASA channel itself.&#8221;</p>
<p>This doesn’t mean that Content ID is perfect, of course.  While there have been plenty of mistakes and even outright <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/youtube-copyright-id-scammers-must-pay-artists-3-3m-restitution-231116/">criminal abuse</a> in the past, YouTube hopes that with the current setup, it has found a balance most rightsholders and content creators can live with. Whether that’s indeed the case, depends on who you ask.</p>
<p>From: <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/">TF</a>, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
